<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Coronation Era &#8211; Blaseball News Network</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/coronation-era/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>HARD HITTING BLASEBALL NEWS</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2023 17:59:19 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.12</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/cropped-BNN-Full-Logo-2.png?fit=32%2C32&#038;ssl=1</url>
	<title>Coronation Era &#8211; Blaseball News Network</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">189429579</site>	<item>
		<title>Blaseball Season CE2 Preview: Estimating the Sunbeams</title>
		<link>/2023/01/22/blaseball-season-ce2-preview-estimating-the-sunbeams/</link>
					<comments>/2023/01/22/blaseball-season-ce2-preview-estimating-the-sunbeams/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Firewall Andrews]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2023 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Editorial]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hellmouth Sunbeams]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BFF]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blaseball]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blaseball news network]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blaseball power rankings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bnn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Coronation Era]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEW]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Predictions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2970</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>I am sure if you asked any Sunbeams fan how they&#8217;re feeling about the second...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2023/01/22/blaseball-season-ce2-preview-estimating-the-sunbeams/">Blaseball Season CE2 Preview: Estimating the Sunbeams</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Blaseball News Network</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-embed alignwide is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<div class="jetpack-video-wrapper"><iframe loading="lazy" title="Blaseball Season CE2 Preview: Estimating the Sunbeams, a Ranking Piece by Blaseball News Network" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/SIfzIAo-UBU?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe></div>
</div><figcaption><em>Audio version available on the BNN YouTube page.</em></figcaption></figure>



<p>I am sure if you asked any Sunbeams fan how they&#8217;re feeling about the second season of Blaseball&#8217;s new Coronation Era, they&#8217;d tell you they&#8217;re a bit nervous about all the attention they&#8217;re getting.</p>



<p>But the attention is for good reason, as one of the league&#8217;s top teams spent the election getting stronger and seems poised to have a great season. After finishing Season N1 with a record of 66-24, the Beams swept the Miami Dale only to stumble and have their kicks taken by the Charleston Shoe Thieves in the second round of the Post Season. But that&#8217;s the same Charleston team that finished below the Moab Hellmouth Sunbeams in the Awful Good division during the Regular Season.</p>



<p>So, what should we expect from the Estimated Sunbeams and the rest of Blaseball in this upcoming season in the Coronation Era? Here&#8217;s a preview of every division, including our panel of power rankers&#8217; predictions for how each division will finish.</p>



<h2>Awful Good</h2>



<p><strong>Predicted order of finish:</strong></p>



<ol><li>Moab Hellmouth Sunbeams (No. 1 overall)</li><li>Charleston Shoe Thieves (No. 2 overall)</li><li>Baltimore Crabs (No. 12 overall)</li><li>Miami Dale (No. 13 overall)</li><li>Philly Pies (No. 15 overall)</li><li>Hades Tigers (No. 20 overall)</li></ol>



<p>While this writer (Firewall Andrews) thinks the Shoe Thieves are the best team in the league, most of our rankings panel picked the Sunbeams, so they get the top spot in the division prediction. However, the panel did put these teams at the top of the overall rankings together, so expect a close fight and a serious title run from whichever team wins the division.</p>



<p>Beyond the two powerhouses, there are three middling teams in the Crabs, Dale and Pies. Miami made the playoffs and saw its roster shuffled a bit with randomized players, but it remains to be seen if they improved enough to take a big step forward in Season 2. The Crabs added the best batter in the Black Hole, but that alone won&#8217;t be enough to shore up their roster, and they should struggle to keep up with the Sunbeams and Thieves. The Pies have a solid but unspectacular team destined for a middle-of-the-road finish.</p>



<p>And the Tigers have Zephyr McCloud, who is very good, but will also be very interesting to watch given their curse. So this is a division with lots of great storylines entering the new season.</p>



<h2>Chaotic Good</h2>



<p><strong>Predicted order of finish:</strong></p>



<ol><li>The Kansas City Breath Mints (No. 5 overall)</li><li>Boston Flowers (No. 11 overall)</li><li>San Francisco Lovers (No. 16 overall)</li><li>Canada Moist Talkers (No. 19 overall)</li><li>New York Millennials (No. 21 overall)</li><li>LA Unlimited Tacos (No. 23 overall)</li></ol>



<p>The Mints were one of four teams to go over 60 wins in Season 1 and return a solid roster that went unchanged in the offseason. They bump down to No. 5 overall following a fourth-place overall finish as the Yellowstone Magic are projected to jump them in overall standing based on our panel&#8217;s picks. I&#8217;m not so sure, and I think the Mints should coast to another 60-win season and playoff berth (birth? is that still a thing?).</p>



<p>The Flowers grew as a group over the offseason via the election and are a team with a lot of promise. This could be one of the top pitching and defense teams in the splort, and I think No. 11 overall is a bit low for Boston. They might give the Mints some trouble but likely finish as a runner-up with a solid shot at the playoffs alongside the Thieves, Beams and Mints.</p>



<p>The rest of this division is going to struggle, especially with all the games they&#8217;re going to have to play against Kansas City and Boston. None of the teams really got any better in the offseason, and the Moist Talkers losing Simon Haley probably makes them a good bit worse. The Season 2 elections will be very important for these four squads.</p>



<h2>Awful Evil</h2>



<p><strong>Predicted order of finish:</strong></p>



<ol><li>Atlantis Georgias (No. 6 overall)</li><li>Core Mechanics (No. 9 overall)</li><li>Broken Ridge Jazz Hands (No. 10 overall)</li><li>Houston Spies (No. 14 overall)</li><li>Dallas Steaks (No. 18 overall)</li><li>Chicago Firefighters (No. 24 overall)</li></ol>



<p>This is definitely a division to watch, as any of four teams could realistically pick up the division title in Season 2. The favorites are definitely Atlantis, with a solid pitching staff and long-time blaseballer Beck Whitney leading a good offense. </p>



<p>But the Core Mechanics have an optimized lineup and promising pitching of their own, the Jazz Hands got a big pitching boost in the offseason to support that was top 10 in OPS a season ago, and the Spies are long shots, but Terrell Bradley&#8217;s alternate is still quite the player and the offense in Houston can hit.</p>



<p>Hello, Steaks! </p>



<p>And the poor Firefighters not only missed out on team-improving blessings, but got tossed a terrible batter by a Houston wimdy of a blessing. Sorry, Chicago.</p>



<h2>Chaotic Evil</h2>



<p><strong>Predicted order of finish:</strong></p>



<ol><li>Mexico City Wild Wings (No. 3 overall)</li><li>Yellowstone Magic (No. 4 overall)</li><li>Seattle Garages (No. 7 overall)</li><li>Hawai&#8217;i Fridays (No. 8 overall)</li><li>Ohio Worms (No. 18 overall)</li><li>Tokyo Lift (No. 22 overall)</li></ol>



<p>If the Awful Evil is &#8220;a division to watch,&#8221; this is &#8220;THE division to watch.&#8221; Loaded with four of our top 10 teams in the power rankings, the Chaotic Evil will see the Wild Wings, downgraded by some awful misfortune and a noteworthy incineration, chased by the upgraded Magic and Garages and the slightly shored up Fridays.</p>



<p>These are four genuinely good teams and it&#8217;s hard to pick a favorite, because most of what we knew about the dominant Wild Wings team of a season ago is not going to be there to start this season. James Boy does return, but without Fletcher Peck and Anastasia Isarobot on the main roster, it&#8217;s left the door wide open for Kiki Avci and the Magic to make a real run at a division title.</p>



<p>Don&#8217;t count out the Garages or Fridays, who both finished ahead of the Magic last season, and while their blessings might not have seemed as flashy and fun as the one Yellowstone got, I wouldn&#8217;t say either team should be discounted as a true contender for this division.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2023/01/22/blaseball-season-ce2-preview-estimating-the-sunbeams/">Blaseball Season CE2 Preview: Estimating the Sunbeams</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Blaseball News Network</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2023/01/22/blaseball-season-ce2-preview-estimating-the-sunbeams/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2970</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
