<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Cal Jones &#8211; Blaseball News Network</title>
	<atom:link href="/author/bensonnewton/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>HARD HITTING BLASEBALL NEWS</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 22:08:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.12</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/cropped-BNN-Full-Logo-2.png?fit=32%2C32&#038;ssl=1</url>
	<title>Cal Jones &#8211; Blaseball News Network</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">189429579</site>	<item>
		<title>Dale Season 13 Recap &#038; Election Analysis</title>
		<link>/2021/03/15/dale-season-13-recap-election-analysis/</link>
					<comments>/2021/03/15/dale-season-13-recap-election-analysis/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Cal Jones]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 21:20:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Miami Dale]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recaps]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1320</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>by Kina McCloud Season 13 was the best season the Miami Dale have had to...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2021/03/15/dale-season-13-recap-election-analysis/">Dale Season 13 Recap &#038; Election Analysis</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Blaseball News Network</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>by <a href="https://twitter.com/KinaMccloud" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Kina McCloud</a></p>



<p>Season 13 was the best season the Miami Dale have had to date. Despite not being playoff ready or being in PartyTime for more than a day during Season 13, they still managed to play quite well. </p>



<p>The Dale’s Season started in very promising fashion and stayed that way even after the MidSeason. Just barely missing the Playoffs, the Dale entered PartyTime on Day 99 with a Record of 55-44. It needs to be stated, some of the pitching rotation really struggled this Season, and the rest of the Dale have been playing hard to make up for their Team’s difficulties.</p>



<p>One of the most shocking events during the Season was a Rogue Umpire incinerating Raúl Leal. RIV. Leal was replaced by Riley Firewall, and Firewall has started off with a decent Season. Future Seasons will tell how well Riley plays with the Dale, but for Season 13 Riley did a good job getting on base.</p>



<p>We saw several Blooddrains through this Season, but both Caleb Novak and Jasmine Washington had Blooddrains that reduced their hitting or baserunning. Beck also got slightly better as a Batter due to blood drains. Other than the Blooddrains, few active events affected the Dale.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Let’s talk about numbers and stlats, they are hard to figure out. Speaking is pretty easy for me, but trying to numbers how hard a player hits is kinda out there. Instead, I want to simply highlight some of the players during the Dale’s Season.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Francisca Sasquatch continues to be incredible at hitting the Blaseball. Fran reliably gets on base, mostly by hitting the Blaseball hard, but can also be expected to walk. We’re not talking only Singles here either, Doubles and Triples are within Fran’s wheelhouse.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; After an Infuse from Season 12, Logan Horseman has been playing way better during Season 13. Logan got on base quite a bit during this Season and mostly by hitting the Blaseball hard. If you like pickles, Logan has quite often stolen bases throughout the Season.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Beck Whitney stole bases nearly as often as Logan did, and Beck scored Runs quite often throughout the Season. Not to mention, Beck also got an improvement from the blood drain this Season.</p>



<p>Qais Dogwalker remains great at striking people out. If my memory serves, Qais only walked 2 players in the entire Season. The fewer people on base, the fewer Runs that can be collected.</p>



<p>Finally, Wyatt Owens, what can I say that doesn’t harsh vibes. Wyatt played several games in the Earlseason that were extremely clutch, and the Miami Dale managed to win those games. That is all.</p>



<p>Did I say last Season was electrifying for the Dale? Well, I was wrong, that was just a zap compared to this Season. By my count, electricity stuck 667 times across the stadiums when the Dale were at bat. I don’t know if this is what the Dale meant by lightshow, but it does the trick.</p>



<p>The Season 13 elections played out mostly to the Miami Dale’s benefit. To start it off, the Crabs exchanged Baldwin Breadwinner for the Dale’s Logan Horseman.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Dale also sent Wyatt Owens to the Shadows and brought out Liam Snail as a replacement. Liam Snail appears to be a solid pitcher, and I await their first game. This is also a solid move by the Fans of the Miami Dale, as Wyatt struggled often on the pitcher’s mound.</p>



<p>Dale then infused Rivers Clembons to increase their stats which was definitely needed after a lackluster pitching Season.</p>



<p>Also, being part of Wild Low’s Bubble Plan, the Dale benefitted from an increase to all of their stats. This increase is applied to every team in the Wild Low, and is a welcome bonus.</p>



<p>One of the Dale’s biggest weaknesses in the previous Seasons was their pitching. With improved pitchers, their Rotation has dramatically improved and could be the change that puts them in the Playoffs. Their Lineup can be improved, but I believe no matter what, the Dale will Party somehow. </p>



<p>DALE!</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2021/03/15/dale-season-13-recap-election-analysis/">Dale Season 13 Recap &#038; Election Analysis</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Blaseball News Network</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2021/03/15/dale-season-13-recap-election-analysis/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1320</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Full Season 12 Recap</title>
		<link>/2021/03/08/the-full-season-12-recap/</link>
					<comments>/2021/03/08/the-full-season-12-recap/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Cal Jones]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 23:42:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Recaps]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1178</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Hello, and welcome back to the consistent Blaseball News Network series where we recap a...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2021/03/08/the-full-season-12-recap/">The Full Season 12 Recap</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Blaseball News Network</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Hello, and welcome back to the consistent Blaseball News Network series where we recap a whole Season at once. It&#8217;s a bit of Hubris.</p>



<p>Blaseball is back, blabey, and with it comes a huge range of changes to the Splort. I&#8217;ll do my best to describe them here&#8230; advanced apologies if I miss something important.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator is-style-wide"/>



<h2>A New Schedule.</h2>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter"><img src="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/EvZ3xDhWQAM6Opc?format=png&amp;name=small" alt="Image"/></figure></div>



<p>Season 12 brings with it a new pace for Blaseball, defined by the Season schedule and planned Siestas. Now, the action will play out on a three weeks on, two weeks off schedule, giving fans, Umps, and Players alike a nice mix of Blaseball playing and relaxation.<br><br>Inside of the Season, we now have numerous sections, separated by the Earlsiesta on Day 27 and the Earlsiesta on Day 72. In addition to being a nice hour break in the midst of a busy week, these Siestas also bring Season-altering implications we&#8217;ll get into later.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<div style="height:60px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<h2>Chorby Short Breaks Blaseball</h2>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="640" height="780" src="/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/pasted-image-0.png?resize=640%2C780&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-1206" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/pasted-image-0.png?w=766&amp;ssl=1 766w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/03/pasted-image-0.png?resize=246%2C300&amp;ssl=1 246w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" data-recalc-dims="1" /><figcaption>Courtesy of Reblase</figcaption></figure></div>



<p>Bright and early, on Day 1 of the Season, Chorby Short of the Yellowstone Magic hit&#8230; a lot of Foul Balls. And kept hitting them. Over and over. In fact, thanks to a weird combination of 0 No Blood Type, their own inclination to always swing, and plenty of matchups with strong opposing pitchers, Chorby set a new record.<br>2,345 foul balls in a Season.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">There were 24,708 foul balls. Chorby hit 2,345 (9.5%) of them. That&#39;s more than the next nine players COMBINED. <a href="https://t.co/9cWzq7SvEF">pic.twitter.com/9cWzq7SvEF</a></p>&mdash; Ifh-Biff, the Data Efreet (@BiffIfh) <a href="https://twitter.com/BiffIfh/status/1367973087245987844?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">March 5, 2021</a></blockquote><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
</div></figure>



<p>Read more about Chorby and their Foul Ball antics in <a href="/2021/03/01/welcome-back-blaseball-chorby-short-hits-198-foul-balls-in-one-game/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">our short article written by q!</a></p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<div style="height:60px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<h2>The Black Hole Hides Secrets</h2>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter"><img src="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/EvaAAnMXMAA-3Xo?format=png&amp;name=small" alt="Image"/></figure></div>



<p>Very early in Season 12 competition, it was discovered that the Black Hole Weather held a secret within. It was the 3-Time ILB Champion Baltimore Crabs, the strongest Team that Blaseball as we know it has ever seen. Of course, they were surrounded with mysterious warnings and even a big KEEP OUT, which held information on a Ballpark within.</p>



<h2>Breach Imminent.</h2>



<p>Within moments of the Earlsieata of Day 27, something was different. Somehow, Baltimore Crabs fans had access to their Ballpark, and were able to Plant a Flag by dedicating one million Coins to its construction&#8230; in under 15 minutes. </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image alignfull"><img src="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/EvoqZxOXAAIWjXV?format=jpg&amp;name=360x360" alt="Image"/></figure>



<p>What this meant, we weren&#8217;t yet sure. We&#8217;ll get there, but we have something else to talk about first. </p>



<h2>Plumbing Issues Abound</h2>



<p>Starting on Day 70, and becoming even more of an issue on Day 71, the Flooding Weather type appeared around the League. Appearing on the Place Bets page for the next Days games, the Weather changed to Black Hole Weather as soon as the Games began proper.  </p>



<p>The source of this flooding was discovered on Day 72, the Latesiesta.</p>



<div style="height:30px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<h2>CLAB DOWN (and friends).</h2>



<p> </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image alignfull size-large"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/EvpjyVHXEAAwfTB.png?w=640&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-1207" data-recalc-dims="1"/></figure>



<div class="wp-block-jetpack-tiled-gallery aligncenter is-style-rectangular"><div class="tiled-gallery__gallery"><div class="tiled-gallery__row"><div class="tiled-gallery__col" style="flex-basis:25.132761819693933%"><figure class="tiled-gallery__item"><img srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Screenshot-2021-03-08-165556.jpg?strip=info&#038;w=431&#038;ssl=1 431w" alt="" data-height="431" data-id="1212" data-link="/?attachment_id=1212" data-url="/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Screenshot-2021-03-08-165556.jpg" data-width="267" src="/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Screenshot-2021-03-08-165556.jpg?ssl=1" layout="responsive"/></figure></div><div class="tiled-gallery__col" style="flex-basis:25.842307538242242%"><figure class="tiled-gallery__item"><img srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Screenshot-2021-03-08-165644.jpg?strip=info&#038;w=394&#038;ssl=1 394w" alt="" data-height="394" data-id="1210" data-link="/?attachment_id=1210" data-url="/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Screenshot-2021-03-08-165644.jpg" data-width="251" src="/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Screenshot-2021-03-08-165644.jpg?ssl=1" layout="responsive"/></figure></div><div class="tiled-gallery__col" style="flex-basis:23.164682277196867%"><figure class="tiled-gallery__item"><img srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Screenshot-2021-03-08-165626.jpg?strip=info&#038;w=431&#038;ssl=1 431w" alt="" data-height="431" data-id="1211" data-link="/?attachment_id=1211" data-url="/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Screenshot-2021-03-08-165626.jpg" data-width="246" src="/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Screenshot-2021-03-08-165626.jpg?ssl=1" layout="responsive"/></figure></div><div class="tiled-gallery__col" style="flex-basis:25.860248364866955%"><figure class="tiled-gallery__item"><img srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/EvpkyHHXEAAdItG.png?strip=info&#038;w=400&#038;ssl=1 400w" alt="" data-height="400" data-id="1213" data-link="/?attachment_id=1213" data-url="/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/EvpkyHHXEAAdItG.png" data-width="255" src="/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/EvpkyHHXEAAdItG.png?ssl=1" layout="responsive"/></figure></div></div></div></div>



<p>The All-Time-Greatest-Team-In-Blaseball, the Baltimore Crabs, had returned, and brought three new Expansion teams with them. We&#8217;re not exactly sure where they came from, but all of them have at least three Championship wins attributed to them. Some even have four! We look forward to observing the effects these  new friends have on the ILB.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<h2>The Finals.</h2>



<p>Yes, we could talk about the incredible feats of both Wild Card teams making it through their opponents (Congrats to the Shoe Thieves and Wild Wings!) or yet another round of Tigerbeams (Hades Tigers vs. Hellmouth Sunbeams) in the Wild League Championships, but we&#8217;re here for all the marbles.</p>



<p>The stage was set for an epic battle between the Hades Tigers, two-time Internet Series Champs, and the Seattle Garages, fresh off of their <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QSr5_8QeLRY&amp;ab_channel=FourthStrike" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Takeover</a> and <a href="https://www.iam8bit.com/products/blaseball-vinyl-soundtrack" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">vinyl release</a>. And what an epic battle it was.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image alignwide"><img src="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/Ev0d0zCWgAMOlBr?format=jpg&amp;name=medium" alt="Image"/></figure>



<p>The Garages handily won a completely normal Game 1, taking an early lead by two runs.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image alignfull"><img src="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/Ev0tk0kXMAQkAFd?format=jpg&amp;name=medium" alt="Image"/></figure>



<p>In extra innings, the Hades Tigers struck back with a win (by two runs, of course!) to even up the First To 3 Series.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image alignfull"><img src="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/Ev07S9bXYAIMxiQ?format=jpg&amp;name=medium" alt="Image"/></figure>



<p>Following another intensely close battle, the Garages pulled ahead in the Series 2-1. Of course, another win by two Runs. </p>



<p>With just one more Win needed for the Garages to take the whole Series, we went on to Game 4.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image alignfull"><img src="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/Ev1IEbDWQAIZK6j?format=jpg&amp;name=medium" alt="Image"/></figure>



<p>Oh.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image alignfull"><img src="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/Ev1T9S3WgAEqXjG?format=jpg&amp;name=900x900" alt="Image"/></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-image alignfull"><img src="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/Ev1T9S4XcAEn8Lz?format=jpg&amp;name=900x900" alt="Image"/></figure>



<p>Just like that, with two quick and dominant victories by the Tigers, after three very close back-and-forth Games, it was over. <br>The Hades Tigers became your Season 12 Blaseball Champions! Congrats to the team.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<h2>RIV.</h2>



<p>Before I end the recap, I&#8217;d like to pay tribute to the two Blaseball Players who passed on to the Hall of Flame this Season.</p>



<h3>RIV <a href="https://www.blaseball.wiki/w/Case_Sports" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">CASE SPORTS</a>.</h3>



<h3>RIV <a href="https://www.blaseball.wiki/w/Joshua_Butt" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">JOSHUA BUTT</a>.</h3>



<p>Welcome to the League, Gita Sparrow and Roscoe Sundae!</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<h2>That&#8217;s all folks.</h2>



<p>Thanks for stopping by yet another Full Season Recap, the first of its kind since the Grand Siesta! I hope you enjoyed it. </p>



<p>Congrats again to the Hades Tigers for their glorious win!<br><br>Remember&#8230; the Commissioner is always doing a good job.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2021/03/08/the-full-season-12-recap/">The Full Season 12 Recap</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Blaseball News Network</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2021/03/08/the-full-season-12-recap/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1178</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
