<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Miami Dale &#8211; Blaseball News Network</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/teams/miami-dale/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>HARD HITTING BLASEBALL NEWS</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2022 09:41:16 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.12</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/cropped-BNN-Full-Logo-2.png?fit=32%2C32&#038;ssl=1</url>
	<title>Miami Dale &#8211; Blaseball News Network</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">189429579</site>	<item>
		<title>The Last Dance: Short Circuit 3 Uptempo Recap</title>
		<link>/2022/02/19/the-last-dance-short-circuit-3-uptempo-recap/</link>
					<comments>/2022/02/19/the-last-dance-short-circuit-3-uptempo-recap/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Blaseball News Network]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 19 Feb 2022 18:10:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Boston Flowers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Breckenridge Jazz Hands]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Core Mechanics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[KC Breath Mints]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Miami Dale]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New York Millenials]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Short Circuits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Yellowstone Magic]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2360</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Organized by: Finn Boston Flowers Having finally rolled a very good team the Boston Flowers...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2022/02/19/the-last-dance-short-circuit-3-uptempo-recap/">The Last Dance: Short Circuit 3 Uptempo Recap</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Blaseball News Network</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Organized by: <a href="http://twitter.com/finnblaseball">Finn</a></p>



<h2 class="has-text-align-center">Boston Flowers</h2>



<p>Having finally rolled a very good team the Boston Flowers were spoiled for choice for our Charge.&nbsp;Our best pitcher, Rosemary Penguin took an early lead due to holding the incredible feat of being undefeated all the way to the Midsea-</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f6a8.png" alt="🚨" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />FEEDBACK DETECTED<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f6a8.png" alt="🚨" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">PEYTON DRYSDALE AND SQUID BROOM WERE SWITCHED IN THE FEEDBACK.</p>



<p>A new challenger arrived from the Yellowstone Magic. Squid Broom was a beloved player by fans since their hatching due to their name. Squid Broom&#8217;s personality is as straightforward as you can get. Please imagine a squid. Please imagine a broom. There you go, that’s Squid Broom.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f6a8.png" alt="🚨" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />FEEDBACK DETECTED<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f6a8.png" alt="🚨" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">SQUID BROOM AND LUCIUS PRINCE WERE SWITCHED IN THE FEEDBACK.</p>



<p>Oh. They got Feedbacked again and are on the Fridays now… except that’s not true. Owing to a “Feature,” certain weather-induced player moves un-happened. Squid Broom was still on the Boston Flowers roster and available for Charging even though their player page listed them on the Hawai’i Fridays.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Flowers chose to lean into the opportunity to commit a data crime and charged Squid Broom, or more accurately the Fridays charged Squid Broom in addition to their chosen charge Moth Frosting.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Flowers now only have two static players, and the Fridays have four and no one has any idea what that’ll mean for the future. Data Crimes!</p>



<h2 class="has-text-align-center"><strong>Breckenridge Jazz Hands</strong></h2>



<p>For the third Circuit in a row, the Jazz Hands had terrible pitching and not-good-enough batting. In the first week, we quickly fell to the bottom of the standings, barely above our long term rivals, the (contemptible) Moist Talkers. We spent the week excited for the Fiesta, and voted leadoff hitter Zee Phantom our party host.</p>



<p>In the Fiesta, we partied a lot Game 1, lost Game 2, and broke Blaseball in Game 3. Squid Psst cemented their status as a Jazz Hands legend by pitching two games simultaneously, getting Night Shifted in one, and Frozen in the other. We split Game 3 with the Pies to end our 3 game series tied 2-2, and somehow “advanced” the next round, only to see it cancelled due to noise complaints.</p>



<p>Like many teams, we choose to host a Sunday Mixer, which accidentally morphed into a Formal. The Divinity boost supercharged our Lineup of inconsistent Home Run hitters, propelling us to a slightly less terrible performance in Week 2. We somehow managed to win two Bloods in the midweek Blood Jam session, gaining Fire blood for “ace” pitcher Lily Cole, and Electric blood for Squid&#8217;s Night Shift replacement Troy Bowman. Unfortunately, we never got a shot at the Title Belt, and failed to qualify for the Postseason.</p>



<p>Zee Phantom had been an early Charge favourite, but Lily Cole rapidly overtook them in Week 2. Lily gained many fans by taking Game 1 of the Fiesta to extra innings so they could party before throwing the game winning strike out— a Shakespearean performance which reminded us of our beloved Lowe Forbes. Lily&#8217;s solid performance in week two and acquisition of Fire blood made them the clear choice to Charge, a decision I&#8217;m sure none of us will come to regret.</p>



<p>&#8211;<a href="http://twitter.com/deafhobbit">deafhobbit</a> </p>



<h2 class="has-text-align-center"><strong>Core Mechanics&nbsp;</strong></h2>



<p>After being presented our team roster for the Circuit, the Mechanics were in a partying mood— after all, being an average team in the strongest division in the League was just the thing to have to make it far in the Midseason Fiesta, or even win it for the promised prize! To top it off, we’d have a lot of chances for partying to make a good run at the second half of the season, so everything was looking great for a successful season.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Other than missing a chance at getting another Bees Manhattan (the Mechs previously charged a player of the same name last Short Circuit), the first week of regular season play went about as expected, we declared our favourite bad pitcher Zebrina Vincent our Guest of Honour, even got a First Round Bye to start the Fiesta…<br><br>What do you mean, the Fiesta got cancelled after the first round? That was not the plan.</p>



<p>Silver lining: the Title Belt still was a fun feature for the Mechs, being holders of one of the two contested belts for way longer than we should&#8217;ve been, finally losing it to the San Francisco Lovers after an eventful and confusing 40-day reign.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The rest of the season was marked by a flurry of Peanuts, with two Allergic and two Yummy reactions happening on our roster. Both yummy reactions happened on Pedro Vixen, an already strong pitcher who ended up almost Expansion Era shaped because of it. After much deliberation, Pedro Vixen was also selected as the team’s Charge target, as they always respected excellence in pitching. Just need to fix our lineup in the next Era, hopefully.</p>



<p>&#8211; Nitro (N1tr00#8811 on Discord)</p>



<h2 class="has-text-align-center"><strong>Kansas City Breath Mints</strong></h2>



<p>Ball 1-0. Ball 2-0. Ball 3-0. Boat Hamless draws a walk.</p>



<p>In Kansas City, Boat Hamless’ plate appearances were so regular you could set your watch by them. The method by which they achieved this differed depending on who you asked— some argue that a boat has no identifiable strike zone, others that Hamless had some sort of psychic barrier that repelled strikes, and one opposing pitcher claimed “They just, like, stand there. Menacingly.” Whatever the cause, fans agreed that Boat’s incredible walk rate, OBP and league leading OPS (ignoring, as another reporter put it, undead invaders from another universe) merited a Charge into the Microphone, optimistic they’ll return to lead the League in walks again.</p>



<p>But Boat alone didn’t win the Breath Mints our second ring! Tube Rust was second in the League for Wins, Yuri O’Lantern had a phenomenal postseason BA of 0.407 and Liv Blather and Levar Downey used their Monitor-approved Blood to improve their performances. Most daringly of all, Layla Chambers pulled off the rarely seen but highly effective “catch fire in the postseason, get replaced with a better pitcher who pitches a save” manoeuvre. A brief timeline of events, with time given relative to the Material plane:</p>



<p>11:08pm UTC: Layla lets in three runs from the Worms</p>



<p>11:09pm UTC: Three fans comment “i don’t care if we win as long as layla dies”, “layla go in the fire <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f449.png" alt="👉" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f525.png" alt="🔥" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />,” “has anyone actually been incined this season?”</p>



<p>11:10pm UTC: Rogue Umpire incinerated Layla Chambers!&nbsp;</p>



<p>Kale Torch then led the team to victory, sporting no losses in their incredibly short career. Wherever they are, I hope they’re enjoying a nice retirement party with the Monitor. And I hope the Mints claim another ring in the Next Era!</p>



<ul><li><a href="http://twitter.com/finnblaseball">Finn</a></li></ul>



<h2 class="has-text-align-center"><strong>Miami Dale</strong></h2>



<p>Season Cinema was one of the better batters on the Dale, holding the team record for homers, sacrifice plays, and-</p>



<p>Wait, this article was supposed to be about our season? Not our Season?</p>



<p>Well, the Miami Dale had something that could certainly be called a season. The Lineup looked promising with bright stars in the form of Season Cinema, William Heat, Lamar Diomira, and Grace Ray. We also had some incredibly good names in the form of Snake Johns, Stone Pretzel, Season Cinema, and William Heat!</p>



<p>Our rotation? Not so much. Norris Manhattan was our only real superstar, but Emma Bark was ruthless despite her 0.4 stars. Which was bad, because we wanted to be good. Or was it good because we wanted to be bad?</p>



<p>Our goals were conflicting, which proved to be our downfall. We scraped past the Midseason Fiesta, couldn’t clutch it in time for the Playoffs, and choked when we got in through Title Belt power.</p>



<p>Now, a keen-eyed reader will notice that the player we Staticked, Adeline Revelry, is not a ‘star.’ They were more of an underwhelming pitcher who was Frozen more often than not.</p>



<p>But the one key trait that put them above all the other contenders (besides their impeccable name) was Blood Jams Vol. I. The wimd blew in our favor and we snatched Electric blood from the Garages in a repeat of history. And it couldn’t have gone to a more appropriately named player.</p>



<p>Despite all the Features, all the losses, and all the Title Belt shenanigans, this is certain to be a circuit the Dale will remember. At least, the ones who were watching will.</p>



<p>CLEAR FLESH CAN’T LOSE MAX VELOCITY DALE!</p>



<p>-Mango (guzmania#4173 on Discord)</p>



<h2 class="has-text-align-center">New York Millennials</h2>



<p>The Gamme 4 Millennials have been a fun bunch to watch; living completely normal lives until a Microphone emerged in the sky and forcing them to play Blaseball, each of them offered something interesting. Irene Fashion, Coyote Stone, Max Quigley, and Calvin Nether had a strong core in our Lineup. Violeta Cantu led the Mills in Triples, Cy Knives and Harold Castillo held their own, and even Cynthia Chalk and Markus Torch would impress with the occasional stolen base and home run. </p>



<p>The pitching staff was mostly solid, with Mordecai Damage sporting a respectable 2.41 ERA. Asher Juice, Dazzy Deng, and Loner Shelley pitched well, and Daniel Darko… was our Guest of Honor!<br><br>Loner Shelley would stand out the most for us, however. A deadpan cosmologist getting the first yummy reaction to a peanut since the Discipline Era, even the Shelled .1 deemed them its progeny. A combination of intense fan interest, solid stats all around, and highly sought after Relevancy (a rare feat among Mills), Loner Shelley was our Charge. While we didn’t perform poorly, we managed to stand out, play about average, and have some memorable moments. Whether it was defeating the Crabs in two simultaneous games, almost facing ourselves in the Fiesta, or Irene receiving a Jersey of Invitation to feature cameos of Deceased players from across universes, I’m proud of these players.<br><br>&#8211;<a href="http://twitter.com/clip_ny">Clip Clipperson</a> </p>



<h2 class="has-text-align-center"><strong>Yellowstone Magic</strong></h2>



<p>The final Short Circuit had us more divided than any other Circuit before it— but that wasn’t a bad thing.</p>



<p>&nbsp;While it looked like we were going to have a singular star player in Squid Broom, them becoming a Flower meant that we had a better chance to see our team as a whole. While we did have players who performed consistently well, there was no longer a singular player on which all of our attention was focused.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Peyton Drysdale and Isaac Puffins were both fearsome baserunners. Henri Kraal and Kay Pleck could hit the ball good. Slosh Chalk had a funny name and played well. Not only was our team statistically well-rounded but it felt like everyone was being equally appreciated by us adoring fans. Everyone had their favourite. And in the end, 56% of our adoration was poured into Errol Wool, our final Charge.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Not only was Wool the only of Magic&#8217;s Charges to be in the Lineup rather than rotation, but there was also no one reason as to why they got our last burst of support.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Though Errol was our Guest of Honor, their buffs from partying ended up being undone by the Ruthless onslaught of Snow, leaving them statistically worse than they started. Instead, we were charmed by the irresistible adoration of a player who was popularly perceived as a sheep. Punny cheers were too good to let go. The image of Charging that thick fluffy fleece with electricity evoked images that we couldn&#8217;t pass up. For some, it was simply that &#8220;Errol Wool&#8221; felt really good to say. Our varied reasoning behind charging Wool is a great reflection of how we experienced these last two weeks as a whole.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This Circuit, it wasn&#8217;t<em> </em>all<em> </em>about the numbers. It was also about the love.</p>



<p>Mal (malgic#8522 on Discord)</p>



<p><em>And a final note &#8211; BNN relies on reports from readers like you to fill out articles! If you’d like to contribute something in the future, head on over to our discord!</em></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2022/02/19/the-last-dance-short-circuit-3-uptempo-recap/">The Last Dance: Short Circuit 3 Uptempo Recap</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Blaseball News Network</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2022/02/19/the-last-dance-short-circuit-3-uptempo-recap/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2360</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Shooting Stars: Miami Dale Dream Team</title>
		<link>/2021/08/14/shooting-stars-miami-dale-dream-team/</link>
					<comments>/2021/08/14/shooting-stars-miami-dale-dream-team/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Blaseball News Network]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 14 Aug 2021 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Miami Dale]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Team Coverage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dream Team]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2050</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>By: Kina McCloud Somebody once told me that the Miami Dale have had some good...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2021/08/14/shooting-stars-miami-dale-dream-team/">Shooting Stars: Miami Dale Dream Team</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Blaseball News Network</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>By: <a href="http://twitter.com/kinamccloud">Kina McCloud</a></p>



<p>Somebody once told me that the Miami Dale have had some good players over their many seasons. This is my attempt to present what is the Dale All-Star Team.&nbsp;</p>



<p>When reading this list, keep in mind that the Miami Dale had Hype for most of Season 24. I have chosen to include a couple of players from this Season because their stats are notable, but not impossible. The second thing I would like to address is that there are a few Players on this list that have had better seasons on other teams. This list is only the Player’s peak performance on the Miami Dale, and I would love to see them included on other team’s All-Stars.&nbsp; As always, there are a couple considerations to keep in mind when making the All-Star teams.</p>



<ol><li>There will be the standard 9 Lineup Players and 5 Pitching Players. Players cannot Elsewhere or Shelled.</li><li>The Selection must represent a single season on that team in their role.</li><li>The player must have played at least one full season with that team.</li><li>A player can only be used once in the 14 positions.</li><li>No Replicas are allowed. Sorry, Lucky Tio.</li></ol>



<p>Without further ado, this is the Miami Dale All-Star Shooting Stars!</p>



<p>Logan Horseman (S17) &#8211; OBP 0.425 &#8211; BA 0.399 &#8211; OPS 1.226 &#8211; SB 74<br>Beck Whitney (S11) &#8211; OBP 0.413 &#8211; BA 0.341 &#8211; OPS 1.083 &#8211; SB 51<br>Rivers Clembons (S20) &#8211; OBP 0.398 &#8211; OPS 1.109 &#8211; BB 55</p>



<p>The first three players in our Lineup are the Dale’s best at getting on base. Season 17 saw Logan Horseman at peak stats post-Election, and this saw Logan becoming Season 17’s League Leader in Batting Average and On-Base Percentage. Season 11 was an incredible Season for Beck Whitney on the Miami Dale with nearly as good stats as peak Logan Horseman well before some of Beck’s peak stars. Finally, we have Rivers Clembons in Season 20 at peak stats as well, with just as solid Season of getting on base.</p>



<p>Francisca Sasquatch (S13) &#8211; SLG 0.703 &#8211; BA 0.367 &#8211; OPS 1.106 &#8211; SF 6<br>Summers Preston (S19) &#8211; SLG 0.676 &#8211; OPS 0.999 &#8211; HR 31<br>Avila Guzman (S11) &#8211; OPS 0.986 &#8211; OBP 0.362</p>



<p>My next two Batters are incredible sluggers. These are the Players that will hit the ball deep into the field and bring multiple players home. Fran has consistently swung with power, but Season 13 was one of Fran’s best. With a batting average that made Fran a League Leader and slugging that still holds up in modern eras this makes Fran the perfect choice to follow up the prior three players. <br><br>Summers Preston was chosen for the same reasons, just in case Fran was walked or struck out. Summers Preston had a strong Home Run record in Season 19 that significantly helps in this position. Finally, I chose Avila Guzman in Season 11 as my sixth position batter. With a solid On-Base Percentage, this makes Avila the perfect choice to reliably get on base and start another drive.</p>



<p>Richmond Harrison (S24) &#8211; OBP 0.378 &#8211; SB 128<br>Jomgy Rosenthal (S24) &#8211; OBP 0.390 &#8211; OPS 1.002<br>Caleb Novak (S4) &#8211; OBP 0.329 &#8211; RBI 50 &#8211; 3B 31</p>



<p>Richmond and Jomgy had solid showings in Season 24 with a bonus from Hype. Richmond Harrison was Season 24’s leader in stolen bases, and both would follow up a drive reliably well. I chose Caleb Novak for Ninth position, surprisingly, because Caleb was an incredible batter for the Era with a specialty in hitting Triples. This would bring multiple players home often and close up the Lineup. As for the Rotation&#8230;. </p>



<p>Qais Dogwalker (S15) &#8211; ERA 1.83 &#8211; SHO 6 &#8211; QS 20 &#8211; BB9 &#8211; 0.1<br>Howell Rocha (S24) &#8211; ERA 1.34 &#8211; SHO 6<br>Sixpack Santiago (S17) &#8211; ERA 2.58 &#8211; SHO 8 &#8211; QS 26 &#8211; BB9 0.2<br>Liam Snail (S18) &#8211; ERA 3.07<br>Don Elliot (S4) &#8211; ERA 3.01 &#8211; BB9 0.9</p>



<p>When it comes to the Miami Dale’s pitching, most of these names will probably be safe choices. The Dale have had a sturdy Rotation for multiple seasons with relatively few changes. Qais Dogwalker is now becoming a strong batter, but I couldn’t stop myself from including Qais in the Rotation. Season 15 was one of Qais’ best seasons with only three walks and a fourth of their games being shutouts. Qais’ Season 15 Postseason appearance was also a shutout with no walks. <br><br>Howell boasts one of the best ERAs in Season 24 despite not being Underhanded. Sixpack Santiago carried Season 17 for Miami Dale’s Rotation. Liam Snail’s best season was included, but Liam still has a lot of room to grow. Finally, a surprise to me, but I found out that Don Elliot was good in Season 4. Keep in mind that this was Season 4’s stats, where the best ERAs were around 2.0.</p>



<p>For a long time, the Miami Dale was the place you party at, but they have since become the place where you party at during the Postseason. Since Season 15, they have only missed two Postseasons, and continue to get better as a team whether their goal is an Overchampionship or an Underchampionship. Who knows what’s over the Horizon for the Miami Dale, but I know they will party on. DALE!</p>



<p>Special bad stat shoutouts!</p>



<p>Caleb Novak with a Career leading 2623 Strikeouts.<br>Rivers Clembons for allowing 1285 Batters to walk in total.</p>



<p><em>This article is part of the </em>Dream Team Series,<em> in which our writers look back on the Discipline and Expansion Eras to create the strongest version of our beloved teams. Read the first in the series <a href="/2021/08/04/all-suns-sunbeams-a-hellmouth-sunbeams-dream-team/">here</a>.</em></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2021/08/14/shooting-stars-miami-dale-dream-team/">Shooting Stars: Miami Dale Dream Team</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Blaseball News Network</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2021/08/14/shooting-stars-miami-dale-dream-team/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2050</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Miami Dale Season 15 Recap</title>
		<link>/2021/04/12/miami-dale-season-15-recap/</link>
					<comments>/2021/04/12/miami-dale-season-15-recap/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Blaseball News Network]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Miami Dale]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Team Coverage]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1579</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>By: Kina McCloud DALE! Coming from a mediocre Season 14, the Miami Dale seemed to...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2021/04/12/miami-dale-season-15-recap/">Miami Dale Season 15 Recap</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Blaseball News Network</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>By: <a href="https://twitter.com/KinaMccloud?s=20">Kina McCloud</a></p>



<p>DALE! </p>



<p>Coming from a mediocre Season 14, the Miami Dale seemed to be heading to another average season. Against all odds, Dale made the Playoffs for the first time in Season 15. They finished second in Wild Low and third in the entire Wild League, but were eliminated from the Playoffs by the Hades Tigers in a 3-1 Series.</p>



<p>Through Season 15, Dale had a Record of 56-43 and 57 total wins. They started the season with good lead and stayed near the top of the Wild Low Division for much of the season. Early PARTYTIME continues to evade the Dale, which is incredibly out of character for them, but don’t worry— they&#8217;re still partying hard. </p>



<p>Riley Firewall came back from Elsewhere on Day 27 after being swept Elsewhere in Season 14. Don Elliot was swept Elsewhere on Day 60 and has not returned, but it’s pretty rad that the ILB sent Don Elliot a bat despite Don being Elsewhere. Hopefully, Don will soon return to Worldwide Field and learn that the Miami Dale made the Playoffs.</p>



<p>Worldwide Field saw some new improvements funded during the Midseason by Fans. An incredible LCD Soundsystem was installed along with a Secret Base. Fans inside Worldwide Field have yet to see the LCD Soundsystem do anything other than sound rad, but Players have been going in and out of the Secret Base. So far, Players have not been changed by the Secret Base here in Miami, but other changes have affected the Players.</p>



<p>Consumers were a constant threat during Season 15 with their attacks resulting in a stat loss. The Miami Dale nearly avoided Consumers this Season, but on Day 99 Consumers attacked Logan Horseman. Despite the Consumer attack, Logan continues to play well and even scored 2 Solo Home Runs on Day 99.</p>



<p>Jasmine Washington had an allergic reaction to a peanut on Day 104 during the Playoffs. It’s always a bummer to see good Players suffer allergic reactions, but Jasmine continues to be good at recognizing opportunities for sacrifice hits.</p>



<p>Avila Guzman was Feedbacked for Jomgy Rolsenthal from the Spies on Day 93. While the Dale will definitely miss Avila, Jomgy is already becoming part of la familia. In the eleven games since being Feedbacked to the Dale, Jomgy has hit 2 Doubles, 5 Singles, 1 Home Run, and stole a base.</p>



<p>During the Election, Cannonball Sports was Exchanged for Lover’s Pitcher Parker Meng. Cannonball, used to being a Batter, will have to flex their Pitching muscles during Season 16.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Parker Meng was recruited by the Crabs right after joining the Dale.</p>



<p>Sixpack Santiago had a Pitching Infusion, increasing their ability quite a bit. Sixpack also received the Living Single Blessing on a 1% chance. Early stat rankers have noted that Sixpack’s pitching is incredibly ruthless and overpowers many batters. It is yet to be seen what Sixpack can do now on the Pitcher’s mound, but they have definitely improved.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The entire ILB got Bats this season during the Election, but Jomgy Rolsenthal received a special Chunky Bat that gave Jomgy the Chunky Modification, giving them &#8220;100% more Power in Peanut Weather.&#8221;</p>



<p>Looking forwards to Season 16, the Dale have a really good pitching Rotation, but their batting Lineup still has some work to do. Early PARTYTIME may just continue to evade the Miami Dale, but despite everything else, they will party.</p>



<p> DALE!</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2021/04/12/miami-dale-season-15-recap/">Miami Dale Season 15 Recap</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Blaseball News Network</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2021/04/12/miami-dale-season-15-recap/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1579</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Dale Season 13 Recap &#038; Election Analysis</title>
		<link>/2021/03/15/dale-season-13-recap-election-analysis/</link>
					<comments>/2021/03/15/dale-season-13-recap-election-analysis/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Cal Jones]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 21:20:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Miami Dale]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recaps]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1320</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>by Kina McCloud Season 13 was the best season the Miami Dale have had to...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2021/03/15/dale-season-13-recap-election-analysis/">Dale Season 13 Recap &#038; Election Analysis</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Blaseball News Network</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>by <a href="https://twitter.com/KinaMccloud" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Kina McCloud</a></p>



<p>Season 13 was the best season the Miami Dale have had to date. Despite not being playoff ready or being in PartyTime for more than a day during Season 13, they still managed to play quite well. </p>



<p>The Dale’s Season started in very promising fashion and stayed that way even after the MidSeason. Just barely missing the Playoffs, the Dale entered PartyTime on Day 99 with a Record of 55-44. It needs to be stated, some of the pitching rotation really struggled this Season, and the rest of the Dale have been playing hard to make up for their Team’s difficulties.</p>



<p>One of the most shocking events during the Season was a Rogue Umpire incinerating Raúl Leal. RIV. Leal was replaced by Riley Firewall, and Firewall has started off with a decent Season. Future Seasons will tell how well Riley plays with the Dale, but for Season 13 Riley did a good job getting on base.</p>



<p>We saw several Blooddrains through this Season, but both Caleb Novak and Jasmine Washington had Blooddrains that reduced their hitting or baserunning. Beck also got slightly better as a Batter due to blood drains. Other than the Blooddrains, few active events affected the Dale.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Let’s talk about numbers and stlats, they are hard to figure out. Speaking is pretty easy for me, but trying to numbers how hard a player hits is kinda out there. Instead, I want to simply highlight some of the players during the Dale’s Season.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Francisca Sasquatch continues to be incredible at hitting the Blaseball. Fran reliably gets on base, mostly by hitting the Blaseball hard, but can also be expected to walk. We’re not talking only Singles here either, Doubles and Triples are within Fran’s wheelhouse.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; After an Infuse from Season 12, Logan Horseman has been playing way better during Season 13. Logan got on base quite a bit during this Season and mostly by hitting the Blaseball hard. If you like pickles, Logan has quite often stolen bases throughout the Season.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Beck Whitney stole bases nearly as often as Logan did, and Beck scored Runs quite often throughout the Season. Not to mention, Beck also got an improvement from the blood drain this Season.</p>



<p>Qais Dogwalker remains great at striking people out. If my memory serves, Qais only walked 2 players in the entire Season. The fewer people on base, the fewer Runs that can be collected.</p>



<p>Finally, Wyatt Owens, what can I say that doesn’t harsh vibes. Wyatt played several games in the Earlseason that were extremely clutch, and the Miami Dale managed to win those games. That is all.</p>



<p>Did I say last Season was electrifying for the Dale? Well, I was wrong, that was just a zap compared to this Season. By my count, electricity stuck 667 times across the stadiums when the Dale were at bat. I don’t know if this is what the Dale meant by lightshow, but it does the trick.</p>



<p>The Season 13 elections played out mostly to the Miami Dale’s benefit. To start it off, the Crabs exchanged Baldwin Breadwinner for the Dale’s Logan Horseman.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Dale also sent Wyatt Owens to the Shadows and brought out Liam Snail as a replacement. Liam Snail appears to be a solid pitcher, and I await their first game. This is also a solid move by the Fans of the Miami Dale, as Wyatt struggled often on the pitcher’s mound.</p>



<p>Dale then infused Rivers Clembons to increase their stats which was definitely needed after a lackluster pitching Season.</p>



<p>Also, being part of Wild Low’s Bubble Plan, the Dale benefitted from an increase to all of their stats. This increase is applied to every team in the Wild Low, and is a welcome bonus.</p>



<p>One of the Dale’s biggest weaknesses in the previous Seasons was their pitching. With improved pitchers, their Rotation has dramatically improved and could be the change that puts them in the Playoffs. Their Lineup can be improved, but I believe no matter what, the Dale will Party somehow. </p>



<p>DALE!</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2021/03/15/dale-season-13-recap-election-analysis/">Dale Season 13 Recap &#038; Election Analysis</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Blaseball News Network</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2021/03/15/dale-season-13-recap-election-analysis/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1320</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>3rd Strike: Another Rogue Ump is Out</title>
		<link>/2021/03/14/3rd-strike-another-rogue-ump-is-out/</link>
					<comments>/2021/03/14/3rd-strike-another-rogue-ump-is-out/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Blaseball News Network]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2021 13:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Miami Dale]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1260</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Written by: Kina McCloud It’s the first Day of Season 13 as the Hades Tigers...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2021/03/14/3rd-strike-another-rogue-ump-is-out/">3rd Strike: Another Rogue Ump is Out</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Blaseball News Network</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Written by: <a href="https://twitter.com/KinaMccloud">Kina McCloud</a></p>



<p>It’s the first Day of Season 13 as the Hades Tigers face the Miami Dale under Solar Eclipse weather. It’s the bottom of the 7th with Mummy Melcon on the pitcher’s mound as a Rogue Umpire tries to incinerate Mummy Melcon, but they’re Fireproof.</p>



<p>Since the Opening of the Forbidden Book, Rogue Umpires have incinerated Players during Solar Eclipses. During Season 7, Fans voted on a new Blessing called The Iffey Jr., and it was awarded to The Miami Dale. The Iffey Jr. was granted to Raúl Leal reducing their stats, but gave Leal the Fireproof modification, allowing them to protect their team from incinerations.</p>



<p>During Season 8, the Internet League Blaseball saw the first known incineration of a rogue umpire when they tried to incinerate the Miami Dale player Beck Whitney. The same Season, the Hades Tigers received the blessing, Anti-Burnout, which made their players immune to incineration. The first known Rogue Umpire incineration was quickly followed up in Season 9 when Fans voted for the Miami Dale to receive the New Kid blessing. There were three Blessings that Season which could incinerate a player, but despite much campaigning the Fans of Miami Dale only got the New Kid Blessing. On most other Teams, this would have incinerated the least idolized player, but not Dale thanks to Raúl and The Iffey Jr. </p>



<p>This leads to the third known Rogue Umpire being incinerated when they tried to incinerate the Tigers’ Melcon. During that game, the ILB first saw that the Fireproof modification on the Hades Tigers could incinerate a Rogue Umpire. This exciting revelation shows that more players can fight Rogue Umpires and defend their Teams which is incredibly rad for Blaseball.</p>



<p>The Hades Tigers have lost several players to incineration including Landry Violence and Mclaughlin Scorpler. The Hades Tigers Official Fan Club had this to say, and a few more scratches into their column is well deserved.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Our fireproofing pays off. Goodbye, rogue umpire! Now to scratch back a few more to our column.</p>&mdash; Hades Tigers Official Fan Club (@HadesBlaseball) <a href="https://twitter.com/HadesBlaseball/status/1368960660747456512?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">March 8, 2021</a></blockquote><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
</div></figure>



<p>When seeing the Hades Tigers incinerate their first rogue umpire, the Fans of the Miami Dale were excited to see another Team not only prevent player incinerations, but also incinerate Rogue Umpires. The Miami Dale Twitter had this to say.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Yo <a href="https://twitter.com/HadesBlaseball?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@HadesBlaseball</a> it feels pretty great no? <a href="https://t.co/8AJCP9ZwfU">pic.twitter.com/8AJCP9ZwfU</a></p>&mdash; Miami Dale (@MiamiBlaseball) <a href="https://twitter.com/MiamiBlaseball/status/1368960269230149634?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">March 8, 2021</a></blockquote><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
</div></figure>



<p>I spoke with <a href="https://twitter.com/AzizHades">Aziz Boatman</a>, beat reporter for the Hades Tigers, about Fans’ reactions to finding out the Tigers could incinerate Rogue Umpires, and the construction of The Ampitheater. While not universal, many Fans saw the immediate potential to take down Rogue Umpires. For many of these same Fans, The Ampitheater was built with the prefab Loge in the hopes that Weather events will occur more frequently.  During Season 13’s Latesiesta, Hades Tigers’ Sixth Circle Stadium, Nicknamed &#8220;The Ampitheater&#8221; completed construction, but it remains to be seen how this affects Solar Eclipses.</p>



<p><em>Dedicated to Raúl Leal and The Iffey Jr. They showed the ILB that the Rogue Umpires could be defeated, and that fight will continue with the Hades Tigers. Party Hard Raúl and Rest. In. Violence.</em></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2021/03/14/3rd-strike-another-rogue-ump-is-out/">3rd Strike: Another Rogue Ump is Out</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Blaseball News Network</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2021/03/14/3rd-strike-another-rogue-ump-is-out/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1260</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Miami Dale Season 12 and Election Recap</title>
		<link>/2021/03/08/miami-dale-season-12-and-election-recap/</link>
					<comments>/2021/03/08/miami-dale-season-12-and-election-recap/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Blaseball News Network]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 14:31:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Miami Dale]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recaps]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1195</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Author: Kina McCloud Season 12 for the Miami Dale was a wild ride, and Dale...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2021/03/08/miami-dale-season-12-and-election-recap/">Miami Dale Season 12 and Election Recap</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Blaseball News Network</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Author: <a href="https://twitter.com/KinaMccloud" data-type="URL" data-id="https://twitter.com/KinaMccloud">Kina McCloud</a></p>



<p>Season 12 for the Miami Dale was a wild ride, and Dale had one of their best seasons to date. Still, they have the Life of the Party, and it would not be a complete season without the Miami Dale being in PARTYTIME.</p>



<p>The Dale started Season 12 by Non-Losing two of their first three games against the Hades Tigers. By the end of Season 12’s midseason, Day 72, the Miami Dale had a decent standing with 36 Wins and 36 Non-Losses to 36 Losses. As the Lateseason continued so did the call of Party Time. They finally entered Party Time on Day 94, and boy was it a party, if I can remember correctly.</p>



<p>This season, the Miami Dale finished fourth in the Wild Low closely behind the Boston Flowers and Houston Spies. The Hellmouth Sunbeams were first in the Wild Low, receiving 11 more wins than the Miami Dale.</p>



<p>It looks to have been a fairly standard Season for the Miami Dale, but there were some notable Blaseball-related events during the Season. Unfortunately, I don’t report on non-Blaseball related events, despite how rad they were.</p>



<p>Raúl Leal was swept away during the Flooding weather, but thankfully Raúl returned after four days.</p>



<p>Beck Whitney partied this Season, and the party vibes appear to have helped Beck as a batter. Beck Whitney will be one to keep an eye on.</p>



<p>Randy Dennis had an allergic reaction to a peanut this Season, but Randy also partied this year and seems to have slightly recovered from the reaction.</p>



<p>Qais Dogwalker continues to be an incredible pitcher, and was even included in <a href="/2021/03/06/the-14-best-players-from-season-12-of-blaseball/">a BNN article of Season 12&#8217;s best players written by Firewall Andrews.</a></p>



<p>I could continue to gush about how psyched I was for all the players on the Miami Dale this Season, but I’m being told to turn it down a notch.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Returning to something incredibly cool, let’s talk about the Electric Miami Dale this Season. Electricity was bouncing across the stadiums and according to the Miami Dale feed, they zapped a whopping 622 strikes this Season. That’s 622 more chances to party, and also more chances to receive a Run!&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Season 12’s election was fairly quiet for the Miami Dale. The Dale voted for the Wills Infuse Logan Horseman and chose Randy Dennis to receive a trust. Logan Horseman was infused and received an increase to their overall ability. Randy Dennis received the trust, Flippers, a modification that helps Runners if immateria floods.</p>



<p>The future looks rad for the Miami Dale, and Party Time will be incredible to see once construction of Worldwide Field is complete. No matter what’s the result of the next season, we still have Miami Dale. This has been McCloud, and as they say, ¡Dale!</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2021/03/08/miami-dale-season-12-and-election-recap/">Miami Dale Season 12 and Election Recap</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Blaseball News Network</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2021/03/08/miami-dale-season-12-and-election-recap/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1195</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
