<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Patrick Caster &#8211; Blaseball News Network</title>
	<atom:link href="/author/patrickwilliamsaee2adfd67/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>HARD HITTING BLASEBALL NEWS</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2021 03:07:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.12</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/cropped-BNN-Full-Logo-2.png?fit=32%2C32&#038;ssl=1</url>
	<title>Patrick Caster &#8211; Blaseball News Network</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">189429579</site>	<item>
		<title>Editorial: When Wins and Losses Became Meaningless</title>
		<link>/2020/10/28/editorial-when-wins-and-losses-became-meaningless/</link>
					<comments>/2020/10/28/editorial-when-wins-and-losses-became-meaningless/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Patrick Caster]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Editorial]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EDITORIAL]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=876</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>In Season 11 of Blaseball, a sort of reset occurred after the Shelled One&#8217;s defeat....</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2020/10/28/editorial-when-wins-and-losses-became-meaningless/">Editorial: When Wins and Losses Became Meaningless</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Blaseball News Network</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In Season 11 of Blaseball, a sort of reset occurred after the Shelled One&#8217;s defeat. But, before its demise, the Sun collapsed and swallowed the Moon while the Sun 2 rose. This set the stage for the only weather to appear in Season 11.</p>



<h2>sun 2</h2>



<p>In a game when the Sun 2 is the active weather condition, a team that gets 10 runs is granted a bonus win, but gives up 10 runs in return. While this can be useful for high scoring teams, this can inadvertently give the actual game win to the opposing team. If the team that got the bonus cannot make up some of the 10 runs they lost, they may not be able to overcome the runs their opponents already had. This means that it is not unlikely for both teams to be granted a win in the case of the Sun 2 weather, boosting both teams in the Blaseball rankings.</p>



<h2>black hole</h2>



<p>The Black hole is the obvious inverse to Sun 2; if a team gets 10 runs in a game with the Black Hole weather, the opposing team loses a win and the Black Hole takes the 10 runs away. In the same vein, this causes the situation of needed to catch up with the opposing team&#8217;s runs in order to ensure you win. However the situation is much worse off when the runs cannot be made back, as at the end of the game it is a net 0 wins for both teams, functionally making it as though both teams lose.</p>



<h2>skill and luck</h2>



<p>While some teams are more likely to get the bonuses of these weather conditions due to their own skill, luck plays a huge role in this case. If are against a stronger team more often in Black Hole weather, you are much more likely to drop in the rankings due to netting 0 or negative wins off of said games, while if you face stronger teams in Sun 2 weather you can still net 0 wins, but you are more likely to land a win against them than in normal circumstances. On the flip side, if you are a stronger team but you happen to be scoring 10+ on Black Hole weather, this could ultimately have you drop in the rankings as you are more likely to not gain a win off that game than in normal circumstances. While it would require more extensive stlatistical research to find exactly how this skewed Season 11 and who was most skewed, it is clear that Sun 2 and Black Hole completely upended how season 11 could have turned out.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2020/10/28/editorial-when-wins-and-losses-became-meaningless/">Editorial: When Wins and Losses Became Meaningless</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Blaseball News Network</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2020/10/28/editorial-when-wins-and-losses-became-meaningless/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">876</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Wild Failure with Mild Enjoyment?</title>
		<link>/2020/09/12/a-wild-failure-with-mild-enjoyment/</link>
					<comments>/2020/09/12/a-wild-failure-with-mild-enjoyment/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Patrick Caster]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2020 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Editorial]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blaseballnewsnetwork.com/?p=436</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>As we all know, Blaseball, and all its unpredictability, is rather enjoyable. Everything from Blessings...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2020/09/12/a-wild-failure-with-mild-enjoyment/">A Wild Failure with Mild Enjoyment?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Blaseball News Network</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>As we all know, Blaseball, and all its unpredictability, is rather enjoyable. Everything from Blessings that boost a whole Team, to weather conditions that trade players between Teams. Unpredictability, in this way, helps keep things interesting. </p>



<p>I was quite excited last season to see some unknown decrees that could bring anything to the table and one thing it brought us, that I was personally excited for too, was a new separation of Leagues. Though the way it split the teams seemed to push toward a predictable outcome I was confident that Blaseball would screw all that up and give us some unexpected turnouts at the end of the season.</p>



<p>I was wrong.</p>



<p>In the Wild League they put the five best Teams in the Wild High division and the five worst teams in Wild Low. This seemed the most ripe for a predictable outcome but I was optimistic. Unfortunately it came out that Wild High ended with majority of the winning power! So much so that they nearly took every seat for Wild in the coming playoffs if it were not for the fact that the Flowers tied the Millenials in wins on the very last Day of the Season. </p>



<p>What was really surprising was that the Mild League followed suit! It contained the top five and bottom five Teams from the middle of the Season 5 standings. With that close of a power spread, you&#8217;d think there would be a bit more of a power struggle. While there was one early, over time it followed a similar pattern of wins. Aside from the outlier of the Pies, all of Mild Low had more losses than wins.</p>



<p>If it were to continue like this, Blaseball could end up with some boring predictability. HOWEVER! I&#8217;m always optimistic, and I believe this won&#8217;t be this case for long. For one, if the Leagues are kept as is, between things like Blessings and possible Enhanced Party Time (a new Decree up for vote this election), the power of the Teams will shift around enough that this obvious predictability will slip away quickly, leaving us guessing a bit more at what sets of Teams are getting into the playoffs. Another possible outcome is the Commissioner may realize how this set up of Teams may seem boring and choose a much more arbitrary structuring technique that would only add to the unusual nature of Blaseball! </p>



<p>The way I see it, this was not the best way to structure the Teams, but as long as they don&#8217;t reshuffled into a new Wild and Mild after each Season, the League will get more interesting in its set up in time. </p>



<p>Until then, I&#8217;ll keep my eye out.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2020/09/12/a-wild-failure-with-mild-enjoyment/">A Wild Failure with Mild Enjoyment?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Blaseball News Network</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2020/09/12/a-wild-failure-with-mild-enjoyment/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">436</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Editorial: The Wild and The Wilder?</title>
		<link>/2020/09/06/editorial-the-wild-and-the-wilder/</link>
					<comments>/2020/09/06/editorial-the-wild-and-the-wilder/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Patrick Caster]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 02:19:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Editorial]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blaseballnewsnetwork.com/?p=362</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>As you likely know, Internet League Blaseball has reshuffled their teams from an Evil League...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2020/09/06/editorial-the-wild-and-the-wilder/">Editorial: The Wild and The Wilder?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Blaseball News Network</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>As you likely know, Internet League Blaseball has reshuffled their teams from an Evil League and Good League to the Wild League and Mild League. </p>



<p>While this is a refreshing change that allows us to see new Blaseball face-offs, it has put together teams in an interesting format. In the Wild League it has Wild High, containing the top 5 teams in the League, and Wild Low, containing the bottom 5 teams in the League. </p>



<p>An obvious criticism of this set up is that the bottom 5 will only lose more to the top 5, but with how the players might play differently with their vibe and the weather conditions, not to mention players switched, incinerated, and shuffled, we might be surprised who will come out on top in this Season!</p>



<p>However, I believe the more wild and entertaining matches will be in the Mild League. This contains the top and bottom of the middle 10 teams in the League. Due to these teams being much closer in ability (blessings and changes non-withstanding) the games in the League will be much harder to predict! Best watch this League very closely because even a little change in stats could really sway this League one way or the other! </p>



<p>No matter the wildness of teams close in skill or the wildness of Blaseball at large, it will be very exciting to see how these teams will interact with their new opponents! Make sure to keep an eye out for all the Blaseball action.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2020/09/06/editorial-the-wild-and-the-wilder/">Editorial: The Wild and The Wilder?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Blaseball News Network</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2020/09/06/editorial-the-wild-and-the-wilder/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">362</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
