<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Firewall Andrews &#8211; Blaseball News Network</title>
	<atom:link href="/author/allgoodcats/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>HARD HITTING BLASEBALL NEWS</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2023 18:05:33 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.12</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/cropped-BNN-Full-Logo-2.png?fit=32%2C32&#038;ssl=1</url>
	<title>Firewall Andrews &#8211; Blaseball News Network</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">189429579</site>	<item>
		<title>Season 2 (CE) Blaseball MVP Vote Results: Who&#039;s Top with Two In The Books?</title>
		<link>/2023/02/09/season-2-ce-blaseball-mvp-vote-results/</link>
					<comments>/2023/02/09/season-2-ce-blaseball-mvp-vote-results/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Firewall Andrews]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2023 21:17:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blaseball]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blaseball mvp]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blaseball news network]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=3067</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Season 2 of the Coronation Era is officially notarized and in the books, and before...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2023/02/09/season-2-ce-blaseball-mvp-vote-results/">Season 2 (CE) Blaseball MVP Vote Results: Who&#039;s Top with Two In The Books?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Blaseball News Network</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-embed alignwide is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<div class="jetpack-video-wrapper"><iframe loading="lazy" title="BLASEBALL Season CE2 MVP Awards, Presented by Blaseball News Network" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9qNo6koyVSw?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe></div>
</div><figcaption><em>Audio version available on the BNN YouTube.</em></figcaption></figure>



<p>Season 2 of the Coronation Era is officially notarized and in the books, and before we embark on siesta, let&#8217;s take a look back at the most outstanding players, or MVP, to hit the diamond over the past 90-plus games.</p>



<p>Many thanks to Dargo4#2798 on Discord for organizing the vote, which you can join as a writer on the <a href="https://discord.gg/zNgbw9M4GP">BNN Discord</a>! </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="640" height="360" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/Copy_of_BNN_C1_MVP_Awards_Breakdowns.png?resize=640%2C360&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-3068" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/Copy_of_BNN_C1_MVP_Awards_Breakdowns.png?resize=1024%2C576&amp;ssl=1 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/02/Copy_of_BNN_C1_MVP_Awards_Breakdowns.png?resize=300%2C169&amp;ssl=1 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/02/Copy_of_BNN_C1_MVP_Awards_Breakdowns.png?resize=768%2C432&amp;ssl=1 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/02/Copy_of_BNN_C1_MVP_Awards_Breakdowns.png?resize=1536%2C864&amp;ssl=1 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/02/Copy_of_BNN_C1_MVP_Awards_Breakdowns.png?w=1920&amp;ssl=1 1920w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/02/Copy_of_BNN_C1_MVP_Awards_Breakdowns.png?w=1280&amp;ssl=1 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></figure>



<h2>Baldwin Jones Memorial Best Batter Award</h2>



<p>Magic Goo?</p>



<p>Yellowstone swept most of the first-place votes for the newly named Baldwin Jones Best Batter award, with Kiki Avci claiming plenty of votes, but <strong>Demet Cabrera</strong> coming out on top with the most-first place votes and overall ballot points to earn the title of batting MVP for Season 2.</p>



<p>Cabrera finished fourth in the league during the regular season with a 1.320 OPS, and among the 48 players with an OPS of 1.000, they had the second-best defensive rating (Outs Above Average) of 24.4.</p>



<p>They slugged an impressive 42 home runs, most in ILB, chipping in 55 doubles and striking out only 40 times.</p>



<p>Defensively, they ranked 17th overall in OAA, holding down the infield for the Magic from First Base and recording an out on almost 80% of the balls hit in their direction.</p>



<p>Their teammate, Avci, does not play quite as good defense back near the wall in center field, but is maybe even better with the bat, leading the league in OPS at 1.432 and hitting 40 triples and 25 homers in Season 2.</p>



<p>Flowers slugger Zack Sanders finished third in the MVP batter voting, one of only two players with over 100 RBIs on the season and third in the league in doubles.</p>



<p>It was Sheri Friday who led the league in doubles, and they come in fourth on our list, with an impressive .393 batting average and 72 doubles.</p>



<p>A full list of results is available at the bottom of the article.</p>



<h2>Anastasia Isarobot Memorial Best Pitcher Award</h2>



<p>The decision for best pitcher came down to the voters choosing between a pair of aces for The Kansas City Breath Mints.</p>



<p><strong>Hatfield Suzuki</strong> claims the top spot in the voting, finishing Season 2 with the best ERA in ILB, the fourth-most strikeouts and the second-best WHIP (walks plus hits allowed per inning pitched). </p>



<p>They allowed only 13 walks all season, striking out 194 batters and allowing only 17 homers.</p>



<p>Their teammate, Plums Blather, was virtually as good as their award-winning teammate, leading the league in strikeouts and WHIP but allowing a few more home runs which must have broken the tie for several voters. </p>



<p>Either way, these two Mints were clearly the best pitchers in the league, and while only one could win, both should be proud of their accomplishments.</p>



<p>Rounding out the voting&#8217;s top three is Don Elliott of the resurgent Chicago Firefighters, who finished with the fourth-best ERA and allowed only six walks, leading to a K/BB ratio that ranked third in ILB.</p>



<p>Honorable mention also goes to Brisket Friendo of the Garages, who had the second best FIP in the league and struck out an impressive 209 batters, and Declan Suzanne of the Crabs, who had the second-best ERA in the splort.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="640" height="360" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/BNN_Anastasia_Isarobot_Memorial_Best_Pitcher_Award_-_Coronation_S1.png?resize=640%2C360&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-3070" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/BNN_Anastasia_Isarobot_Memorial_Best_Pitcher_Award_-_Coronation_S1.png?resize=1024%2C576&amp;ssl=1 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/02/BNN_Anastasia_Isarobot_Memorial_Best_Pitcher_Award_-_Coronation_S1.png?resize=300%2C169&amp;ssl=1 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/02/BNN_Anastasia_Isarobot_Memorial_Best_Pitcher_Award_-_Coronation_S1.png?resize=768%2C432&amp;ssl=1 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/02/BNN_Anastasia_Isarobot_Memorial_Best_Pitcher_Award_-_Coronation_S1.png?resize=1536%2C864&amp;ssl=1 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/02/BNN_Anastasia_Isarobot_Memorial_Best_Pitcher_Award_-_Coronation_S1.png?w=1920&amp;ssl=1 1920w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/02/BNN_Anastasia_Isarobot_Memorial_Best_Pitcher_Award_-_Coronation_S1.png?w=1280&amp;ssl=1 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></figure>



<h2>Postseason MVP Award</h2>



<p>As expected, the champion Sunbeams nearly swept the voting for Postseason MVP, with tide-turning grand slammer <strong>Guozhi Ong</strong> earning the most votes to claim the trophy. However, the award could have gone to any number of Beams, including Grizz El Sayed and Kajjala Aliyev for countless clutch hits, Dunn Keyes for a great performance on the mound in the final game, or any of the other Moab Hellmouth players listed in the chart above.</p>



<h2>Full Results</h2>



<p><strong>Best Batter Award:</strong></p>



<ol><li>Demet Cabrera, Yellowstone Magic</li><li>Kiki Avci, Yellowstone Magic</li><li>Zack Sanders, Boston Flowers</li><li>Sheri Friday, Core Mechanics</li><li>Kajjala Aliyev, Moab Hellmouth Sunbeams</li><li>Katja Twain, Mexico City Wild Wings</li><li>Baldwin Jones, Mexico City Wild Wings</li><li>Grizz El Sayed, Moab Hellmouth Sunbeams</li><li>Alvie Kesh, San Francisco Lovers</li><li>Famous Owens, Hawai&#8217;i Fridays</li><li>Penelope Berkowitz, Charleston Shoe Thieves</li><li>Roscoe Sundae, Tokyo Lift</li></ol>



<p><strong>Best Pitcher Award:</strong></p>



<ol><li>Hatfield Suzuki, Kansas City Breath Mints</li><li>Plums Blather, Kansas City Breath Mints</li><li>Don Elliott, Chicago Firefighters</li><li>Brisket Friendo, Seattle Garages</li><li>Declan Suzanne, Baltimore Crabs</li><li>Vernon Sierpinski, Mexico City Wild Wings</li><li>Dunn Keyes, Moab Hellmouth Sunbeams</li><li>Javier Lotus, Boston Flowers</li><li>Agan Harrison, Dallas Steaks</li><li>Sexton Wheerer, Hawai&#8217;i Fridays</li><li>Donia Dollie, San Francisco Lovers</li></ol>



<p><strong>Postseason MVP:</strong></p>



<ol><li>Guozhi Ong, Moab Hellmouth Sunbeams</li><li>Kajjala Aliyev, Moab Hellmouth Sunbeams</li><li>Grizz El Sayed, Moab Hellmouth Sunbeams</li><li>Dunn Keyes, Moab Hellmouth Sunbeams</li><li>Zack Sanders, Boston Flowers</li><li>Pangolin Ruiz, Moab Hellmouth Sunbeams</li><li>Ã–zlem Suttner, Moab Hellmouth Sunbeams</li><li>Mooney Doctor, Moab Hellmouth Sunbeams</li><li>Kiki Avci, Yellowstone Magic</li><li>Donia Dollie, San Francisco Lovers</li><li>Demet Cabrera, Yellowstone Magic</li></ol>



<p></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2023/02/09/season-2-ce-blaseball-mvp-vote-results/">Season 2 (CE) Blaseball MVP Vote Results: Who&#039;s Top with Two In The Books?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Blaseball News Network</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2023/02/09/season-2-ce-blaseball-mvp-vote-results/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3067</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Blaseball Season CE2 Preview: Estimating the Sunbeams</title>
		<link>/2023/01/22/blaseball-season-ce2-preview-estimating-the-sunbeams/</link>
					<comments>/2023/01/22/blaseball-season-ce2-preview-estimating-the-sunbeams/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Firewall Andrews]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2023 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Editorial]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hellmouth Sunbeams]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BFF]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blaseball]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blaseball news network]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blaseball power rankings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bnn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Coronation Era]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEW]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Predictions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2970</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>I am sure if you asked any Sunbeams fan how they&#8217;re feeling about the second...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2023/01/22/blaseball-season-ce2-preview-estimating-the-sunbeams/">Blaseball Season CE2 Preview: Estimating the Sunbeams</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Blaseball News Network</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-embed alignwide is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<div class="jetpack-video-wrapper"><iframe loading="lazy" title="Blaseball Season CE2 Preview: Estimating the Sunbeams, a Ranking Piece by Blaseball News Network" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/SIfzIAo-UBU?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe></div>
</div><figcaption><em>Audio version available on the BNN YouTube page.</em></figcaption></figure>



<p>I am sure if you asked any Sunbeams fan how they&#8217;re feeling about the second season of Blaseball&#8217;s new Coronation Era, they&#8217;d tell you they&#8217;re a bit nervous about all the attention they&#8217;re getting.</p>



<p>But the attention is for good reason, as one of the league&#8217;s top teams spent the election getting stronger and seems poised to have a great season. After finishing Season N1 with a record of 66-24, the Beams swept the Miami Dale only to stumble and have their kicks taken by the Charleston Shoe Thieves in the second round of the Post Season. But that&#8217;s the same Charleston team that finished below the Moab Hellmouth Sunbeams in the Awful Good division during the Regular Season.</p>



<p>So, what should we expect from the Estimated Sunbeams and the rest of Blaseball in this upcoming season in the Coronation Era? Here&#8217;s a preview of every division, including our panel of power rankers&#8217; predictions for how each division will finish.</p>



<h2>Awful Good</h2>



<p><strong>Predicted order of finish:</strong></p>



<ol><li>Moab Hellmouth Sunbeams (No. 1 overall)</li><li>Charleston Shoe Thieves (No. 2 overall)</li><li>Baltimore Crabs (No. 12 overall)</li><li>Miami Dale (No. 13 overall)</li><li>Philly Pies (No. 15 overall)</li><li>Hades Tigers (No. 20 overall)</li></ol>



<p>While this writer (Firewall Andrews) thinks the Shoe Thieves are the best team in the league, most of our rankings panel picked the Sunbeams, so they get the top spot in the division prediction. However, the panel did put these teams at the top of the overall rankings together, so expect a close fight and a serious title run from whichever team wins the division.</p>



<p>Beyond the two powerhouses, there are three middling teams in the Crabs, Dale and Pies. Miami made the playoffs and saw its roster shuffled a bit with randomized players, but it remains to be seen if they improved enough to take a big step forward in Season 2. The Crabs added the best batter in the Black Hole, but that alone won&#8217;t be enough to shore up their roster, and they should struggle to keep up with the Sunbeams and Thieves. The Pies have a solid but unspectacular team destined for a middle-of-the-road finish.</p>



<p>And the Tigers have Zephyr McCloud, who is very good, but will also be very interesting to watch given their curse. So this is a division with lots of great storylines entering the new season.</p>



<h2>Chaotic Good</h2>



<p><strong>Predicted order of finish:</strong></p>



<ol><li>The Kansas City Breath Mints (No. 5 overall)</li><li>Boston Flowers (No. 11 overall)</li><li>San Francisco Lovers (No. 16 overall)</li><li>Canada Moist Talkers (No. 19 overall)</li><li>New York Millennials (No. 21 overall)</li><li>LA Unlimited Tacos (No. 23 overall)</li></ol>



<p>The Mints were one of four teams to go over 60 wins in Season 1 and return a solid roster that went unchanged in the offseason. They bump down to No. 5 overall following a fourth-place overall finish as the Yellowstone Magic are projected to jump them in overall standing based on our panel&#8217;s picks. I&#8217;m not so sure, and I think the Mints should coast to another 60-win season and playoff berth (birth? is that still a thing?).</p>



<p>The Flowers grew as a group over the offseason via the election and are a team with a lot of promise. This could be one of the top pitching and defense teams in the splort, and I think No. 11 overall is a bit low for Boston. They might give the Mints some trouble but likely finish as a runner-up with a solid shot at the playoffs alongside the Thieves, Beams and Mints.</p>



<p>The rest of this division is going to struggle, especially with all the games they&#8217;re going to have to play against Kansas City and Boston. None of the teams really got any better in the offseason, and the Moist Talkers losing Simon Haley probably makes them a good bit worse. The Season 2 elections will be very important for these four squads.</p>



<h2>Awful Evil</h2>



<p><strong>Predicted order of finish:</strong></p>



<ol><li>Atlantis Georgias (No. 6 overall)</li><li>Core Mechanics (No. 9 overall)</li><li>Broken Ridge Jazz Hands (No. 10 overall)</li><li>Houston Spies (No. 14 overall)</li><li>Dallas Steaks (No. 18 overall)</li><li>Chicago Firefighters (No. 24 overall)</li></ol>



<p>This is definitely a division to watch, as any of four teams could realistically pick up the division title in Season 2. The favorites are definitely Atlantis, with a solid pitching staff and long-time blaseballer Beck Whitney leading a good offense. </p>



<p>But the Core Mechanics have an optimized lineup and promising pitching of their own, the Jazz Hands got a big pitching boost in the offseason to support that was top 10 in OPS a season ago, and the Spies are long shots, but Terrell Bradley&#8217;s alternate is still quite the player and the offense in Houston can hit.</p>



<p>Hello, Steaks! </p>



<p>And the poor Firefighters not only missed out on team-improving blessings, but got tossed a terrible batter by a Houston wimdy of a blessing. Sorry, Chicago.</p>



<h2>Chaotic Evil</h2>



<p><strong>Predicted order of finish:</strong></p>



<ol><li>Mexico City Wild Wings (No. 3 overall)</li><li>Yellowstone Magic (No. 4 overall)</li><li>Seattle Garages (No. 7 overall)</li><li>Hawai&#8217;i Fridays (No. 8 overall)</li><li>Ohio Worms (No. 18 overall)</li><li>Tokyo Lift (No. 22 overall)</li></ol>



<p>If the Awful Evil is &#8220;a division to watch,&#8221; this is &#8220;THE division to watch.&#8221; Loaded with four of our top 10 teams in the power rankings, the Chaotic Evil will see the Wild Wings, downgraded by some awful misfortune and a noteworthy incineration, chased by the upgraded Magic and Garages and the slightly shored up Fridays.</p>



<p>These are four genuinely good teams and it&#8217;s hard to pick a favorite, because most of what we knew about the dominant Wild Wings team of a season ago is not going to be there to start this season. James Boy does return, but without Fletcher Peck and Anastasia Isarobot on the main roster, it&#8217;s left the door wide open for Kiki Avci and the Magic to make a real run at a division title.</p>



<p>Don&#8217;t count out the Garages or Fridays, who both finished ahead of the Magic last season, and while their blessings might not have seemed as flashy and fun as the one Yellowstone got, I wouldn&#8217;t say either team should be discounted as a true contender for this division.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2023/01/22/blaseball-season-ce2-preview-estimating-the-sunbeams/">Blaseball Season CE2 Preview: Estimating the Sunbeams</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Blaseball News Network</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2023/01/22/blaseball-season-ce2-preview-estimating-the-sunbeams/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2970</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Who were the MVPs of Season 1 of the Coronation Era of Blaseball?</title>
		<link>/2023/01/20/who-were-the-mvps-of-season-1-of-the-coronation-era/</link>
					<comments>/2023/01/20/who-were-the-mvps-of-season-1-of-the-coronation-era/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Firewall Andrews]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 21:20:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Editorial]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Team Coverage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blaseball]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blaseball mvp]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blaseball news network]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bnn]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2893</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Blaseball has returned, and so have the talented athletes who take to the Field every...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2023/01/20/who-were-the-mvps-of-season-1-of-the-coronation-era/">Who were the MVPs of Season 1 of the Coronation Era of Blaseball?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Blaseball News Network</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-embed alignwide is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<div class="jetpack-video-wrapper"><iframe loading="lazy" title="BLASEBALL Season N1 MVP Awards, Presented by Blaseball News Network" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/NLip1yReV2M?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe></div>
</div><figcaption><em>Audio version available on the BNN YouTube.</em></figcaption></figure>



<p class="has-text-align-left">Blaseball has returned, and so have the talented athletes who take to the Field every day and play the games. But not every player is equal. Some are better than others. Some are the best. We&#8217;re here to talk about the best.</p>



<p>Many thanks to Dargo4#2798 on Discord for organizing the first Most Valuable Player voting of the new era, which let a panel of Blaseball statisticians and observers vote on the best batters and pitchers of Season 1, plus the postseason MVP and some honorable mentions.</p>



<p>So without any more delay, here are the best players from Season 1 of the Coronation Era of Blaseball.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/Copy_of_BNN_C1_MVP_Awards_Breakdowns-1.png?w=640&#038;ssl=1" alt="A list of players named in MVP voting is available at the bottom of the article." class="wp-image-2896" height="auto" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/Copy_of_BNN_C1_MVP_Awards_Breakdowns-1.png?w=1920&amp;ssl=1 1920w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/01/Copy_of_BNN_C1_MVP_Awards_Breakdowns-1.png?resize=300%2C169&amp;ssl=1 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/01/Copy_of_BNN_C1_MVP_Awards_Breakdowns-1.png?resize=1024%2C576&amp;ssl=1 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/01/Copy_of_BNN_C1_MVP_Awards_Breakdowns-1.png?resize=768%2C432&amp;ssl=1 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/01/Copy_of_BNN_C1_MVP_Awards_Breakdowns-1.png?resize=1536%2C864&amp;ssl=1 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/01/Copy_of_BNN_C1_MVP_Awards_Breakdowns-1.png?w=1280&amp;ssl=1 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></figure>



<h2>Best Batter Award</h2>



<p>Dargo&#8217;s panel named five players per ballot, and across 24 ballots, every single ballot contained one name: <strong>Fletcher Peck</strong>.</p>



<p>The Mexico City Wild Wings&#8217; batter finished with 24 home runs, tied for seventh in ILB, and a 1.234 OPS that was second among full-time players behind only Kiki Avci. </p>



<p>Peck also played sound defense, recording an out on over 78% of the balls hit in their direction, which ranks comfortably in the top half of ILB defenders.</p>



<p>Doing all of this as the league&#8217;s RBI leader and second-best run scorer was more than enough to cement their status as the near-consensus MVP of the first season of the era.</p>



<h2>Anastasia Isarobot Memorial Best Pitcher Award</h2>



<p>The winner of the first Best Pitcher Award of the era is also the new namesake for the award, as they will be honored posthumously after being the target of an incineration by the Umpires following the opening of the Forbidden Book in the Season 1 elections.</p>



<p><strong>Anastasia Isarobot</strong> was the only pitcher to top 200 strikeouts in Season 1, finishing with a 2.24 ERA and a 17-1 record on the mound. They also issued only four walks, the second-lowest total in the league behind Randy Dennis of the Flowers.</p>



<p>Isarobot was a star in the league and their talents will be missed, but their legacy lives on through this award.</p>



<h2>BNN Postseason MVP Award</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/BNN_Anastasia_Isarobot_Memorial_Best_Pitcher_Award_-_Coronation_S1.png?w=640&#038;ssl=1" alt="A list of players named in MVP voting is available at the bottom of the article." class="wp-image-2897" height="auto" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/BNN_Anastasia_Isarobot_Memorial_Best_Pitcher_Award_-_Coronation_S1.png?w=1920&amp;ssl=1 1920w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/01/BNN_Anastasia_Isarobot_Memorial_Best_Pitcher_Award_-_Coronation_S1.png?resize=300%2C169&amp;ssl=1 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/01/BNN_Anastasia_Isarobot_Memorial_Best_Pitcher_Award_-_Coronation_S1.png?resize=1024%2C576&amp;ssl=1 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/01/BNN_Anastasia_Isarobot_Memorial_Best_Pitcher_Award_-_Coronation_S1.png?resize=768%2C432&amp;ssl=1 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/01/BNN_Anastasia_Isarobot_Memorial_Best_Pitcher_Award_-_Coronation_S1.png?resize=1536%2C864&amp;ssl=1 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/01/BNN_Anastasia_Isarobot_Memorial_Best_Pitcher_Award_-_Coronation_S1.png?w=1280&amp;ssl=1 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></figure>



<p>While the Wild Wings sweep the Regular Season awards, it was the Shoe Thieves who snuck into the Internet Series and ran away with the victory.</p>



<p>With that in mind, it was their unlikely hero, Ankle Halifax, who gets the nod as Postseason MVP. With several clutch hits in the Post Season, including multiple home runs in the Internet Series and the Series-deciding hit to win it all for Charleston, they stood out ahead of teammate Penelope Berkowitz, who provided world-class defense for the Thieves throughout the playoffs.</p>



<h2>Honorable Mentions</h2>



<p>Your guess is as good as ours, but here are some players the panel wished to shout out!</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/C1_MVP_HMs-1.png?w=640&#038;ssl=1" alt="A list of players named in MVP voting is available at the bottom of the article." class="wp-image-2898" height="auto" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/C1_MVP_HMs-1.png?w=1920&amp;ssl=1 1920w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/01/C1_MVP_HMs-1.png?resize=300%2C169&amp;ssl=1 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/01/C1_MVP_HMs-1.png?resize=1024%2C576&amp;ssl=1 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/01/C1_MVP_HMs-1.png?resize=768%2C432&amp;ssl=1 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/01/C1_MVP_HMs-1.png?resize=1536%2C864&amp;ssl=1 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/01/C1_MVP_HMs-1.png?w=1280&amp;ssl=1 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></figure>



<h2>Full results</h2>



<p><strong>Best Pitcher Award:</strong></p>



<ol><li>Anastasia Isarobot</li><li>Marco Escobar</li><li>Plums Blather</li><li>Mehdi Caper</li><li>Dunn Keyes</li><li>Mooney Doctor</li><li>Premjeet Liu</li><li>Erin Jesaulenko</li><li>Waverly Mori</li><li>Malik Romayne</li></ol>



<p><strong>Best Batter Award:</strong></p>



<ol><li>Fletcher Peck</li><li>Kiki Avci</li><li>Stretch Sutton</li><li>Katja Twain</li><li>Baldwin Jones</li><li>Jorge Owens</li><li>Mckinney Vaughan</li><li>Sheri Friday</li><li>Jammy Decksetter</li><li>Jira Sealegs</li><li>Demet Cabrera</li></ol>



<p><strong>Postseason MVP:</strong></p>



<ol><li>Ankle Halifax</li><li>Penelope Berkowitz</li><li>Fletcher Peck</li><li>Kaj Statter Jr.</li><li>Yusef Puddles</li><li>Fish Summer</li><li>Anastasia Isarobot</li><li>Alexandria Rosales</li></ol>



<p><strong>Honorable Mentions:</strong></p>



<ul><li>Demet Cabrera</li><li>James Boy</li><li>Malin Hsu</li><li>Penelope Berkowitz</li><li>Premjeet Liu</li><li>Yusef Puddles</li><li>Allan Kranch</li><li>Anastasia Isarobot</li><li>Baldwin Jones</li><li>Beck Whitney</li><li>Blimp Hardison</li><li>Elijah Valenzuela</li><li>Elip Dean</li><li>Emmet Atomic</li><li>Fletcher Peck</li><li>Grizz El-Sayid</li><li>Hatfield Suzuki</li><li>Jammy Decksetter</li><li>Jefferson de la Cruz</li><li>Jorge Owens</li><li>Lorcan Smaht</li><li>Mordecai Kingbird</li><li>Nathaniel Wilds</li><li>Nori Bluegrass</li><li>Ovid Schofield</li><li>Randy Dennis</li><li>Roscoe Sundae</li><li>Scratch Deleuze</li><li>Son Jensen</li><li>Stevenson Heat</li><li>Terrel Bradley</li><li>Vanille Okidoke</li><li>Waverly Mori</li><li>whichever ffs pitcher had the sub 2 ERA</li><li>Zack Sanders</li></ul>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2023/01/20/who-were-the-mvps-of-season-1-of-the-coronation-era/">Who were the MVPs of Season 1 of the Coronation Era of Blaseball?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Blaseball News Network</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2023/01/20/who-were-the-mvps-of-season-1-of-the-coronation-era/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2893</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Charleston Shoe Thieves are Champions: Blaseball Internet Series Recap</title>
		<link>/2023/01/14/charleston-shoe-thieves-are-champions-blaseball-internet-series-recap/</link>
					<comments>/2023/01/14/charleston-shoe-thieves-are-champions-blaseball-internet-series-recap/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Firewall Andrews]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 01:39:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Charleston Shoe Thieves]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blaseball]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blaseball news network]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bnn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[charleston]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shoe thieves]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2871</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ankle Halifax was the hero after a dramatic, controversial Game 4 finished with the Charleston...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2023/01/14/charleston-shoe-thieves-are-champions-blaseball-internet-series-recap/">Charleston Shoe Thieves are Champions: Blaseball Internet Series Recap</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Blaseball News Network</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-embed alignwide is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<div class="jetpack-video-wrapper"><iframe loading="lazy" title="Charleston Shoe Thieves Season N1 Championship, a Blaseball News Network Recap by Firewall Andrews" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/TC8zBvZnLig?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe></div>
</div><figcaption><em>Audio version available on BNN&#8217;s YouTube.</em></figcaption></figure>


<p>Ankle Halifax was the hero after a dramatic, controversial Game 4 finished with the Charleston Shoe Thieves crowned as ILB champions.</p>


<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Premjeet Liu on the mound for the Thieves, 14-4 with a 2.09 ERA this season.<br><br>For the Wings, Anastasia Isarobot, who went 17-1 with a remarkable 204/4 K/BB ratio.</p>&mdash; Blaseball Facts &amp; Figures (@BFFBlaseball) <a href="https://twitter.com/BFFBlaseball/status/1614382439714914376?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 14, 2023</a></blockquote><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
</div></figure>



<p>In Game 1, the Wings turned to their ace Anastasia Isarobot, who hardly let the Thieves get on base for most of the game. The occasional single or double gave Charleston hope, but a rally in the ninth would put the Shoe Thieves on the edge of a miracle comeback. Fish Summer, a veteran with lots of playoff experience, couldn&#8217;t deliver as the final batter and Mexico City picked up a 1-0 series lead with a 1-0 win.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Game 2 will see the Shoe Thieves&#39; Alexandria Rosales (13-5, 2.35 ERA) taking on Enid Slumps (12-6 with a 3.40 ERA) for the Wild Wings.</p>&mdash; Blaseball Facts &amp; Figures (@BFFBlaseball) <a href="https://twitter.com/BFFBlaseball/status/1614390202675372032?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 14, 2023</a></blockquote><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
</div></figure>



<p>In Game 2, Alexandria Rosales was able to keep the Wild Wings&#8217; offense at bay, directing them to take lots of shots at center field, where defensive star Penelope Berkowitz roams. The Shoe Thieves got huge homers from Kaj Statter Jr. and Ankle Halifax and worked out of a late jam to pick up the 3-0 win and even the series.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Shoe Thieves win! Defensive star Penelope Berkowitz secures the third out to get Alexandria Rosales out of a jam in the top of the ninth and Charleston has tied the series at 1-1.</p>&mdash; Blaseball Facts &amp; Figures (@BFFBlaseball) <a href="https://twitter.com/BFFBlaseball/status/1614403274177908736?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 14, 2023</a></blockquote><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
</div></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">The Game 3 pitching matchup has the Wings sending Engine Eberhardt to the mound (15-3, 3.31 ERA) to face the Shoe Thieves, who counter with Kit Adamses (13-5, 2.06 ERA).</p>&mdash; Blaseball Facts &amp; Figures (@BFFBlaseball) <a href="https://twitter.com/BFFBlaseball/status/1614404168269135872?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 14, 2023</a></blockquote><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
</div></figure>



<p>The Wings got off to a great start in Game 3, getting to Kit Adamses early thanks to Jefferson de la Cruz. But it would be Ankle Halifax delivering another huge home run in a back-and-forth game that would put the Shoe Thieves ahead 4-3 heading into the ninth. Fletcher Peck got on with a triple and a chance to tie it in the final frame, but Adamses kept  it cool and the Thieves went up 2-1, but not before chipping in a couple of bonus runs in the bottom of the ninth.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">And now it gets interesting:<br><br>Washer Barajas, 13-5, 2.22 ERA but a bit of a walk problem, will take the mound for the Shoe Thieves to take on the Wings&#39; Vernon Sierpinski, 17-1, 2.11 ERA and no walk problems at all.</p>&mdash; Blaseball Facts &amp; Figures (@BFFBlaseball) <a href="https://twitter.com/BFFBlaseball/status/1614419405894557701?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 15, 2023</a></blockquote><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
</div></figure>



<p>I wrote on Twitter that things were about to get interesting in Game 4 &#8230; and boy, did things get interesting. The Thieves got out to an early lead, with Jammy Decksetter finally getting hot with a homer to put them up 2-0 in the fourth. Then, the Wings would lose their best offensive player, as Fletcher Peck was hit by a falling Yusef Puddles in the middle of the game. This inspired the Wings to step things up, and they&#8217;d rally in the sixth inning to tie the game.</p>



<p>Then. Controversy.</p>



<p>Late in the game, with a runner on second, Carter O&#8217;Connor made decent contact with a pitch and reached first safely, only to be tagged out at second trying to extend the play to a double. The runner from second, Baldwin Jones, touched home plate, but the Umpires did not recognize it as a score. Either they deemed Jones didn&#8217;t score before the tag was applied, or missed it &#8230; but either way, we played on tied 2-2.</p>



<p>Then, it was Ankle Halifax one last time, batting in the bottom of the ninth with Fish Summer on second, who would smoke a ball through the infield to score Summer and win the title for the Shoe Thieves, three games to one.</p>



<p>It&#8217;s the second championship for the Shoe Thieves, who finished the regular season second in the Awful Good division with a 65-25 record.</p>



<p>The Shoe Thieves&#8217; previous championship, in Season 9, was also won in the bottom of the ninth, on a Stu Trololol three-run homer.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2023/01/14/charleston-shoe-thieves-are-champions-blaseball-internet-series-recap/">Charleston Shoe Thieves are Champions: Blaseball Internet Series Recap</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Blaseball News Network</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2023/01/14/charleston-shoe-thieves-are-champions-blaseball-internet-series-recap/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2871</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The best and worst stat for every Blaseball team in NEW Season 1</title>
		<link>/2023/01/14/the-best-and-worst-stat-for-every-blaseball-team-in-new-season-1/</link>
					<comments>/2023/01/14/the-best-and-worst-stat-for-every-blaseball-team-in-new-season-1/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Firewall Andrews]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2023 20:28:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BFF]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blaseball]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blaseball news network]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bnn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEW]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stats]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2867</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The Post Season of Blaseballâ€™s first season of the new era continues, but Firewall continues...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2023/01/14/the-best-and-worst-stat-for-every-blaseball-team-in-new-season-1/">The best and worst stat for every Blaseball team in NEW Season 1</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Blaseball News Network</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-embed alignwide is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<div class="jetpack-video-wrapper"><iframe loading="lazy" title="Teams BestWorst Stats for Season N1, a Blaseball News Network Analysis Piece by Firewall Andrews" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/wJ2ad0LdywU?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe></div>
</div><figcaption><em>Audio version available on BNN&#8217;s YouTube.</em></figcaption></figure>



<p class="has-text-align-left">The Post Season of Blaseballâ€™s first season of the new era continues, but Firewall continues to want to look back, considering the notable stats from the regular season that was.</p>



<p>After 90 games, every team showed strengths and weaknesses, so hereâ€™s a look at what every team did best, and where they should be looking to shore things up during the elections.</p>



<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f531.png" alt="ðŸ”±" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> <strong>Atlantis Georgias &#8211;</strong> The Georgias scored tons of runs in lots of different ways, not relying on the homer but instead leading the league in sacrifice hits and ranking fifth in triples. This is the sort of power hitting that should translate well into this new era of defensive blaseball. However, the Georgias do need to strike out more batters, racking up the fewest Ks of any team (517) for the first season.</p>



<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f980.png" alt="ðŸ¦€" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> <strong>Baltimore Crabs &#8211;</strong> The Crabsâ€™ pitching staff allowed the fewest home runs in the league in Season N1, which is great! Itâ€™s also one of few standout areas for Baltimore, who need a bit more star power to move up in the standings. The team finished in the bottom third of the league in total bases and runs scored on offense this past season.</p>



<p><strong><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f339.png" alt="ðŸŒ¹" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></strong> <strong>Boston Flowers &#8211;</strong> Only the Lift allowed more home runs than the Flowersâ€™ pitching staff this season, which will hold Boston back in its aspirations in future seasons. However, they also struck out the third-most batters, so there is a glimmer of hope that the underlying stats for the Boston bullpen are better than what we saw on the field in this first campaign of the new era.</p>



<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f450.png" alt="ðŸ‘" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> <strong>Breckenridge Jazz Hands &#8211;</strong> The Jazz Hands were two strikeouts above last place among pitching staves, not a great place to be However, they picked up the fourth-most triples in the league, showing that they still know how to put on a captivating show in Breckenridge.</p>



<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/26aa.png" alt="âšª" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> <strong>Canada Moist Talkers &#8211;</strong> The Talkers have some of the weaker power bats in the league, ranking 21st in team slugging percentage and near the bottom in runs scored, as well. However, no team hit more singles than the Canadians, which means with a bit of time in the gym and those singles becoming extra-base hits, the Moist Talkers could be in for a quick turnaround.</p>



<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f45f.png" alt="ðŸ‘Ÿ" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> <strong>Charleston Shoe Thieves &#8211;</strong> The Shoe Thieves come in second in singles hit behind the Talkers but donâ€™t have quite the same problem picking up extra-base hits, ranking seventh in total bases in ILB this season. However, they may want to avoid putting runners on first, as they hit into the fifth-most double plays of any team in ILB in the first season of the NEW era.</p>



<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f525.png" alt="ðŸ”¥" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> <strong>Chicago Firefighters &#8211; </strong>Letâ€™s focus on the positives first and note that the Firefighters finished with a respectable 656 strikeouts, good for 10th among bullpens in ILB. However, the offense was â€¦ bad, scoring the fewest runs and racking up the second-worst slugging percentage in ILB.</p>



<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f6e0.png" alt="ðŸ› " class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> <strong>Core Mechanics &#8211;</strong> A team after my own heart, the Mechs finished with the third-best strikeout-to-walk ratio in ILB this past season at 6.37 whiffs per free pass. However, the team was pretty mediocre at the plate, and while they have no clear weaknesses there, they failed to crack the top 10 in any meaningful team hitting stat outside of doubles and avoiding whiffs. That said .. itâ€™s hard to find a negative thing to say about this team, and theyâ€™re one to watch for the future.</p>



<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f969.png" alt="ðŸ¥©" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> <strong>Dallas Steaks &#8211;</strong> Despite having one of the best sluggers in the league in Vanille Okidoke, the Steaks finished in the bottom five among offenses in OPS and on-base percentage. The pitching staff was great at keeping runners off the bases, though, as the team ranked ninth in WHIP (walks and hits allowed per inning pitched).</p>



<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f405.png" alt="ðŸ…" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> <strong>Hades Tigers &#8211;</strong> Mehdi Caper was the lone bright spot on a pitching staff that led ILB in walks issued in Season N1, where the Tigers really lacked consistency on the mound. The offense wasnâ€™t much better, ranking last in OPS. Sorry, Tigers fans â€¦ there really isnâ€™t much good to say about this team right now. Hades had arguably the worst statistical season in ILB to start the new era. I guess we can break the rules and shout out Stevenson Heat for leading ILB in double plays on defense? Thatâ€™s a positive!</p>



<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f334.png" alt="ðŸŒ´" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> <strong>Hawai&#8217;i Fridays &#8211;</strong> The Fridays are a team I love to hate, as they are strong in one of my favorite stat categories (pitching strikeouts per nine innings, where they rank sixth), but poor in one of my other go-to stats for pitching strength (walks per nine innings, a stat in which they are 10th worst). This balances out to a very mid K/BB ratio, but it worked for Hawaiâ€™i, as they finished with the fourth-best ERA in the sport.</p>



<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f575.png" alt="ðŸ•µ" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> <strong>Houston Spies &#8211;</strong> Only the Tigers issued more walks than the Spies, who definitely need to shore up their pitching staff in the offseason. However, the bats showed some solid pop, coming in at No. 6 in ILB in slugging percentage in Season N1.</p>



<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f36c.png" alt="ðŸ¬" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> <strong>Kansas City Breath Mints &#8211; </strong>The Mintsâ€™ pitching staff was FANTASTIC on the mound, racking up the second-most strikeouts in ILB (752) and the second-best WHIP (0.825). Itâ€™s hard to find many negatives about the team, but they were one of only five teams to score over 300 runs but strike out over 600 times. Thatâ€™s the one thing we could see propelling the Mints to an even better season: a bit more discipline at the plate.</p>



<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f32e.png" alt="ðŸŒ®" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> <strong>LA Unlimited Tacos &#8211;</strong> However, no team struck out as often as the Tacos, who finished with just shy of 800 whiffs in 90 games at the plate. Not good. On the flip side, the team was great at keeping the ball in the park on defense, allowing the fourth-fewest homers per nine innings among pitching staffs to start the new era.</p>



<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f357.png" alt="ðŸ—" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> <strong>Mexico City Wild Wings &#8211;</strong> Well, they scored the most runs (by a wide margin), hit the most homers, struck out the least and had the best OPS by nearly 100 points on offense, all while sporting a solid pitching staff. Itâ€™s really hard to find a negative, but if we had to â€¦ they did hit into the most double plays of any team in Blaseball. I guess they can work on improving that?</p>



<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f6a4.png" alt="ðŸš¤" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> <strong>Miami Dale &#8211;</strong> The Dale ranked sixth in triples with 50 (50 3s, backwards thatâ€™s 305). But they did struggle with keeping the ball in the park, allowing the third-most homers per nine innings of any pitching staff (more than one per game).</p>



<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f31e.png" alt="ðŸŒž" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> <strong>Moab Hellmouth Sunbeams &#8211;</strong>The BEAMS! Oh, how I love you, Beams. No team came close to Moab Hellmouth in the strikeout to walk ratio category, with the Sunbeams at 8.24 and the next closest squad at 6.67. However, that strong command came with a bit of risk, as the Beams also allowed the fifth-most homers per nine innings in the league.</p>



<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f4f1.png" alt="ðŸ“±" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> <strong>New York Millennials &#8211;</strong> The Mills really lacked pop at the plate, hitting only 66 homers, fourth-fewest in Season N1. However, they were one of four teams to finish with at least 700 hits, 30 triples and 100 sacrifices but with 30 or fewer double plays. (This was a reach, sorry Mills fans, not a lot of good to say about the stats this season).</p>



<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f40c.png" alt="ðŸŒ" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> <strong>Ohio Worms &#8211;</strong> Only the Tigers had a worst strikeout to walk ratio than the Worms, who whiffed only 532 batters in 90 games. The offense was far from consistent but did offer a lot of pop, as the team was one of only 10 with more than 80 home runs on the campaign. </p>



<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f967.png" alt="ðŸ¥§" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> <strong>Philly Pies &#8211;</strong> The Piesâ€™ pitching staff was solid to start the new era, ranking top 10 in K/BB and strikeouts, but could stand to improve at the plate with a team OPS of just 0.600, fourth-worst in ILB..</p>



<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f48b.png" alt="ðŸ’‹" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> <strong>San Francisco Lovers &#8211;</strong> It was all or nothing for the Lovers, who had a respectable 90 home runs to rank eighth among ILB teams, but posted the sixth-worst slugging percentage at 0.367. The Lovers will need to make more consistent contact to take advantage of the clear home-run power on their roster.</p>



<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f3b8.png" alt="ðŸŽ¸" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> <strong>Seattle Garages &#8211;</strong> The Garages were solid on both sides of the ball to start the new era with few obvious weak points, so weâ€™ll start with the bad news: They did walk 220 batters, one of eight teams to issue over 200 free passes from the mound. However, they were top 10 in strikeouts and on the offensive side, top five in OPS as a team.</p>



<p><strong><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f3cb.png" alt="ðŸ‹" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></strong> <strong>Tokyo Lift &#8211;</strong> No team allowed more hits than the Lift, who were the only team to break 10 hits allowed per nine innings in Season N1. The bats werenâ€™t much better, but they were one of only four teams to hit 40 or more triples and 30 or fewer double plays. (Sorry to the Lift, as well, just not a lot of positive things to say.)</p>



<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/2728.png" alt="âœ¨" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> <strong>Yellowstone Magic &#8211;</strong> The ball was flying at the Park Park this season, as the Magic ranked third in OPS in the league, led by star Kiki Avci. However, the pitching was nothing special, as the Magic were one of seven teams with fewer than 600 strikeouts on the mound to begin the new era..</p>



<p>Special thanks to Abyline on the SIBR Discord for help parsing and compiling season stats!</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2023/01/14/the-best-and-worst-stat-for-every-blaseball-team-in-new-season-1/">The best and worst stat for every Blaseball team in NEW Season 1</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Blaseball News Network</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2023/01/14/the-best-and-worst-stat-for-every-blaseball-team-in-new-season-1/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2867</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Every Blaseball Team&#8217;s Star of the New Era</title>
		<link>/2023/01/14/top-players-season-n1-firewall-andrews/</link>
					<comments>/2023/01/14/top-players-season-n1-firewall-andrews/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Firewall Andrews]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2023 15:07:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BFF]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blaseball]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blaseball news network]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bnn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEW]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stats]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2862</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Season N1 is in the books, and the Post Season is underway. But before we...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2023/01/14/top-players-season-n1-firewall-andrews/">Every Blaseball Team&#8217;s Star of the New Era</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Blaseball News Network</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-embed alignwide is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<div class="jetpack-video-wrapper"><iframe loading="lazy" title="Every Blaseball Teams Season N1 Star, a Blaseball News Network Analysis Piece by Firewall Andrews" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/M9bxB8adUVw?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe></div>
</div><figcaption><em>Audio version available on BNN&#8217;s YouTube.</em></figcaption></figure>



<p>Season N1 is in the books, and the Post Season is underway. But before we get too far into the drama of the playoff and the intrigue of the elections, letâ€™s take a look back at the notable players from the first season of the new era of ILB.</p>



<p>Specifically, hereâ€™s one player you should know about from every Blaseball club!</p>



<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f531.png" alt="ðŸ”±" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> <strong>Atlantis Georgias &#8211;</strong> And I immediately cheat and start with two names: Let me tell you all about Son Jensen and Emmet Atomic. The Georgiaâ€™s ace, Jensen, went 14-4 and issued only seven walks while striking out 121. Atomic finished with a 12-6 record, walking only four batters and whiffing 86. These arenâ€™t astronomical strikeout figures, but with walks that low, these are tough pitchers to beat.</p>



<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f980.png" alt="ðŸ¦€" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> <strong>Baltimore Crabs &#8211;</strong> It was a fairly quiet season in Baltimore compared to the teamâ€™s storied history in the previous eras of Blaseball, and the team really lacked in star power. However, Ramirez Winters is a name to know. They finished with 10 triples, one of only 29 players to accomplish the feat, and led the Crabs in homers, RBIs and batting average, while also chipping in with 21 sacrifices, top 10 in the league.</p>



<p><strong><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f339.png" alt="ðŸŒ¹" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></strong> <strong>Boston Flowers &#8211;</strong> Amir Murphy cracked the top 20 in ILB with 166 strikeouts in the first season of the era, but was unlucky to walk away with a 7-11 pitching record thanks in part to low run support but also a bit of a homer problem. If Murphy can keep the ball in the park in the future, this flower should blossom in the coming seasons.</p>



<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f450.png" alt="ðŸ‘" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> <strong>Breckenridge Jazz Hands &#8211;</strong> Veteran ILBer Qais Dogwalker finished in the top 20 of ILB in OPS and led the Jands in doubles, triples, sacrifice hits, RBIs and batting average. Their 23 sacrifice hits were tied for fourth in the league.</p>



<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/26aa.png" alt="âšª" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> <strong>Canada Moist Talkers &#8211;</strong> Simon Haley! The former slugger for the Shoe Thieves who hit the splortâ€™s first pentaslam is back as a pitcher, and showed off some incredible skills this season. Haley sat down 128 batters via the strikeout while walking only 5, giving them the seventh best strikeout-to-walk ratio for Season N1. (Eris Street? Theyâ€™re good, too.)</p>



<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f45f.png" alt="ðŸ‘Ÿ" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> <strong>Charleston Shoe Thieves &#8211;</strong> Jammy Decksetter was a star on offense for the Thieves, ranking 13th in Blaseball in OPS and being one of only 17 players to hit 20 or more homers over the 90 game season.</p>



<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f525.png" alt="ðŸ”¥" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> <strong>Chicago Firefighters &#8211; </strong>It wasnâ€™t exactly a season to write home about for the Firefighters, but they have a promising talent on the mound in Karato Rangel. The teamâ€™s ace was one of only seven pitchers to strike out more than 150 batters and walk 10 or fewer over the course of the regular season.</p>



<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f6e0.png" alt="ðŸ› " class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> <strong>Core Mechanics &#8211;</strong> We have to talk about Chorby Short, right? The fan favorite took to the mound and was incredible, demonstrating pinpoint precision with 114 strikeouts and only four walks, the third-best K/BB ratio in ILB. The Mechanics as a whole were great at keeping the ball in the zone, issuing the third-fewest walks of any pitching staff.</p>



<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f969.png" alt="ðŸ¥©" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> <strong>Dallas Steaks &#8211;</strong> Vanille Okidoke was one of 15 ILBers to hit for better than .330 on the season, adding 28 home runs, second in the league. Thatâ€™s more homers than the next three best players from the Steaks combined!</p>



<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f405.png" alt="ðŸ…" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> <strong>Hades Tigers &#8211;</strong> Mehdi Caper was one of 15 pitchers to surpass 170 strikeouts in Season N1, and finished with the best ERA in blaseball at 1.37. However, poor run support meant they could only manage a 9-9 win-loss record, but thatâ€™s not a great reflection of the dominant season on the mound for Caper, who was arguably the best pitcher in blaseball.</p>



<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f334.png" alt="ðŸŒ´" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> <strong>Hawai&#8217;i Fridays &#8211;</strong> Famous Owens lived up to their name with a noteworthy performance at the plate, ranking 16th in OPS in the league (one of 18 players above 1.000) and leading the Fridays in homers (19, tied with Valenzuela), RBIs (65) and hits (122).</p>



<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f575.png" alt="ðŸ•µ" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> <strong>Houston Spies &#8211;</strong> Terrell Bradley finished 12th in the league in RBIs for the Spies, thanks in large part to 20 sacrifice hits, one of only 15 players to hit that mark, and the only player with at least 20 sacrifices and 15 home runs.</p>



<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f36c.png" alt="ðŸ¬" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> <strong>Kansas City Breath Mints &#8211; </strong>Thanks to the facts machine, you already know about Stretch Sutton, so letâ€™s instead focus on Plums Blather. Part of a dominant Mintsâ€™ pitching staff, Plums struck out 190 batters, third-most in ILB, and finished with the fifth-best ERA (1.71).</p>



<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f32e.png" alt="ðŸŒ®" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> <strong>LA Unlimited Tacos &#8211;</strong> Despite joining midseason, Malik Destiny led the Tacos in triples hit with 13 (tied for ninth in the league in two-thirds the plate appearances of other leaders) and posted the second-best OPS on their team.</p>



<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f357.png" alt="ðŸ—" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> <strong>Mexico City Wild Wings &#8211;</strong> Thereâ€™s almost too much to say about this team, so letâ€™s focus on someone whose name doesnâ€™t show up on the home run leaderboard: Letitia Diop. Diop had the second-most sacrifice hits in Blaseball with 25, and theyâ€™re one of four Wings players in the top eight in the league in runs batted in.</p>



<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f6a4.png" alt="ðŸš¤" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> <strong>Miami Dale &#8211;</strong> Malik Romayne posted the third-best ERA in ILB in Season N1, ranking seventh with 178 strikeouts and walking only 12. Their 14-4 record helped lift the Dale into the Post Season to begin the new era.</p>



<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f31e.png" alt="ðŸŒž" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> <strong>Moab Hellmouth Sunbeams &#8211;</strong> Jorge Owens was the only non-Wings player to top 80 runs batted in this season, tying for the league lead with 86. That, combined with their 26 homers, helped propel a well-rounded Moab Hellmouth team into the Post Season and a spot in the Semifinals.</p>



<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f4f1.png" alt="ðŸ“±" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> <strong>New York Millennials &#8211;</strong> Not much went right for the Mills in Season N1, but Alejandro Navarro is a keeper on the mound. They finished with 111 strikeouts and only eight walks, a stat line hardly deserving of a 7-11 win-loss record.</p>



<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f40c.png" alt="ðŸŒ" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> <strong>Ohio Worms &#8211;</strong> Malin Hsu joined the 20 home run club in Season N1 for the Worms while finishing with the eighth-best batting average in blaseball. They led Ohio in pretty much every category, including hits, singles, doubles, RBIs and OPS.</p>



<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f967.png" alt="ðŸ¥§" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> <strong>Philly Pies &#8211;</strong> Jira Sealegs was one of only four players with more than 20 home runs and fewer than 35 strikeouts. They made good, consistent contact for the Pies, as well, ranking 10th in ILB in batting average on the season.</p>



<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f48b.png" alt="ðŸ’‹" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> <strong>San Francisco Lovers &#8211;</strong> Alvie Kesh finished tied for ninth in RBIs with 67, slugging 22 homers and batting .310 to lead the Lovers in all three categories. They also struck out 14 fewer times than their next closest teammate, Kiki Junior Jr.</p>



<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f3b8.png" alt="ðŸŽ¸" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> <strong>Seattle Garages &#8211;</strong> A run-producer who doesnâ€™t rely on the long ball, Hendricks Richardson finished with 68 RBIs despite only 11 homers. Thatâ€™s thanks in part to 54 doubles, tied for 11th in the league, and a respectable 14 sacrifice hits.</p>



<p><strong><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f3cb.png" alt="ðŸ‹" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></strong> <strong>Tokyo Lift &#8211;</strong> Tad Blortles finished with a 7-11 record on the season for the Lift, and while they did give up a good number of homers, to finish with 99 strikeouts to only six walks shows good promise for a Lift team looking for big gains in Season N2.</p>



<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/2728.png" alt="âœ¨" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> <strong>Yellowstone Magic &#8211;</strong> The Leagueâ€™s OPS leader (not counting Natha Spruce, who played in only a few games for the Lift) was the Magicâ€™s own Kiki Avci, one of only 19 players to hit for a â€œquadruple doubleâ€ on the season (more than 10 of each: singles, doubles, triples and home runs). They also drove in 73 runs, fourth-best in the league.</p>



<p>Special thanks to Abyline on the SIBR Discord for help parsing and compiling season stats!</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2023/01/14/top-players-season-n1-firewall-andrews/">Every Blaseball Team&#8217;s Star of the New Era</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Blaseball News Network</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2023/01/14/top-players-season-n1-firewall-andrews/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2862</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How the Baltimore Crabs built a dynasty the right way</title>
		<link>/2021/03/13/how-the-baltimore-crabs-built-a-dynasty-the-right-way/</link>
					<comments>/2021/03/13/how-the-baltimore-crabs-built-a-dynasty-the-right-way/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Firewall Andrews]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 22:28:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Editorial]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1257</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>I know that just reading that headline will raise blood pressures and get the discourse...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2021/03/13/how-the-baltimore-crabs-built-a-dynasty-the-right-way/">How the Baltimore Crabs built a dynasty the right way</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Blaseball News Network</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>I know that just reading that headline will raise blood pressures and get the discourse flowing among Blaseball fans, and all I ask is that you give me a chance to explain myself. </p>



<p>I am not a Crabs fan. Not by a longshot. I rejoiced as a Shoe Thief when Stu Trololol did the impossible to Shame the Crabs and win the Season 9 finals. I have cast votes for nine seasons, often thinking &#8220;does it even matter?&#8221;</p>



<p>But it&#8217;s worth taking a look at the history of the Crabs to see how they got to where they are, and what exactly the fanbase did to build their dynasty franchise. It&#8217;s not all about sheer voting power and numbers. It&#8217;s about picking the right blessings and a bit of good fortune along the way.</p>



<h2>The Early Days</h2>



<p>Back in Season 1, the Crabs were not a powerhouse, but they did make some moves in the very first election. Sparsely attended by a much smaller fanbase at the time, the Crabs were able to grab Polkadot Patterson in an early trade, and boosted their team by 6% overall. This set a trend for the Crabs. This defined their approach.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">The Season 1 Crabs roster. How did this bunch of genuinely awful disaster goblins win anything??? Lmao <a href="https://t.co/qKKNEOzBOW">pic.twitter.com/qKKNEOzBOW</a></p>&mdash; The Baltimore Crabs <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f980.png" alt="ðŸ¦€" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f441.png" alt="ðŸ‘" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> blaseball.com (@BlaseballCrabs) <a href="https://twitter.com/BlaseballCrabs/status/1368044802550468610?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">March 6, 2021</a></blockquote><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
</div></figure>



<p>In each season since, the Crabs made the biggest impact to their lineup with votes for blessings that do two things: Steal the best player at something, or boost their entire team in every stat or in a specific stat.</p>



<p>That wouldn&#8217;t happen again until Season 3, because in Season 2 the team actually lost Patterson to the Defection blessing and cast the most votes for a 10% hitting boost but did not win. In the third election, Baltimore stole Nagomi Mcdaniel and also had the most votes for &#8220;steal best pitcher&#8221; but did not have their ticket drawn.</p>



<p>In Season 4, the team overwhelmingly voted for two blessings that stole the best players from their lineup to their rotation, and vice versa. This brought speedster Tillman Henderson and Oliver Notarobot into the lineup, and Finn James into the rotation. These blessings were not that popular, and the Crabs dominated the voting, seeing a great chance to really improve their lineup and exploiting a soft spot in the league&#8217;s collective voting plans.</p>



<h2>The Dynasty Begins</h2>



<p>In the following two seasons, the crabs would win blessings for improved baserunning and to steal the best player (Nagomi Mcdaniel, who they lost the season before), plus voting heavily in a moderately popular &#8220;pitch from the plate&#8221; blessing to grab Axel Trololol. They also led the vote for Vulture (steal the best player) and Spin Attack (team speed boost) but did not win them.</p>



<p>The dynasty was well underway, to the point where the league overwhelmingly voted for the team to be cut off from blessings via Bless Off in Season 7.</p>



<p>So to that point, the team had stolen the best player in the league multiple times, and pretty much every other blessing they voted for and won focused on boosting stats across the board on their team.</p>



<p>That&#8217;s a trend worth noting.</p>



<h2>The Roller Coaster</h2>



<p>The Crabs had grown into an unstoppable force by Season 8, and led the voting in several blessings: Home Field Advantage, a team-wide boost to play better at home; Flame-Resistant Foam, to prevent incinerations for the whole team; Replacement Elbows, a boost to most of the pitching staff; Affinity for Crows, a team-wide boost in Bird weather; and Precognition, a boost for three hitters, and lost. They lost each of those votes, but almost all of them were team-wide boosts or protections.</p>



<p>In Season 9, they voted for and won the fifth base bubble, a team and division-wide buff, and had the most votes for but did not win Tag Team Hitting, which would have boosted their entire lineup. The trend continues.</p>



<p>In Season 10 &#8230; all of those boosts paid off. The Crabs went Up. They were gone. They lost players in the election, but did it even matter? (We know it did.) Mcdaniel was gone, again, as well as star pitcher Montgomery Bullock.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">guess whose back<br>back again<br>crabs are back<br>tell a friend <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f980.png" alt="ðŸ¦€" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f441.png" alt="ðŸ‘" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> <a href="https://t.co/uDCFAxEV4B">pic.twitter.com/uDCFAxEV4B</a></p>&mdash; The Baltimore Crabs <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f980.png" alt="ðŸ¦€" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f441.png" alt="ðŸ‘" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> blaseball.com (@BlaseballCrabs) <a href="https://twitter.com/BlaseballCrabs/status/1367521658425212933?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">March 4, 2021</a></blockquote><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
</div></figure>



<h2>Sticking to the Plan</h2>



<p>But in Season 12 &#8230; they were back, and they were up to their old tricks. In their first election back in the ILB, they voted for Fourth Strike to counteract Flinch, with 96% of their Enrich Will votes, and called up Jacoby Podcast to replace Bevan Underbuck in the rotation with a 40% probability. Stealing their best shadows player, and a team-wide buff. The team even lucked into a team-wide defense boost from The Rack, despite not casting the most votes for this very popular blessing.</p>



<p>The combination of a solid foundation from team-wide buffs and star power from steals and exchanges has created an absolutely unstoppable Blaseball franchise in Baltimore. The Crabs have combined their voting power (fanbase) with voting strategy to always build and improve a roster that now has impossibly good defense and base-running, even after countless losses and steals. </p>



<p>So if you&#8217;re bummed to see the Crabs win it all <em>again</em>, you&#8217;re not alone. Lots of fans are not happy to see the title brought home to the Crabitat once again. But look to what the Crabs did over their first few seasons in Blaseball and what they continue to do now that they&#8217;ve returned, and bring that back to your team.</p>



<p>Because ultimately, many of the Crabs&#8217; notable blessings wins were not the most popular or contested blessing of the season. They weren&#8217;t the most flashy or interesting. They weren&#8217;t the most fun with all of the good memes on the Discord.</p>



<p>They were just the right picks at the right time. That&#8217;s been the story for the Crabs.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2021/03/13/how-the-baltimore-crabs-built-a-dynasty-the-right-way/">How the Baltimore Crabs built a dynasty the right way</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Blaseball News Network</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2021/03/13/how-the-baltimore-crabs-built-a-dynasty-the-right-way/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1257</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>BNN&#8217;s Midseason Power Ranking Review: Taco Baco</title>
		<link>/2021/03/10/bnns-midseason-power-ranking-review-taco-baco/</link>
					<comments>/2021/03/10/bnns-midseason-power-ranking-review-taco-baco/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Firewall Andrews]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 04:05:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Power Rankings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Videos]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1226</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>In the first episode of BNN&#8217;s newest show, the Midseason Power Ranking Review, host Dan...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2021/03/10/bnns-midseason-power-ranking-review-taco-baco/">BNN&#8217;s Midseason Power Ranking Review: Taco Baco</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Blaseball News Network</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In the first episode of BNN&#8217;s newest show, the Midseason Power Ranking Review, host <a href="https://twitter.com/Leto">Dan</a> is joined by <a href="https://twitter.com/haskins_luckey">Luckey Haskins</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/FirewallAndrews">Firewall Andrews</a> and special guest <a href="https://twitter.com/ilianaquorum">iliana</a> from <a href="https://twitter.com/SIBROfficial">SIBR</a> to discuss the state of play in Season 13 and what went right &#8212; and wrong &#8212; in our <a href="/2021/03/07/blaseball-power-rankings-for-season-13/">Season 13 power rankings</a>. </p>



<p>The crew discuss the origins of the power rankings and talk a bit about their approach, then dive into the main topic &#8230;</p>



<p>Are the Tacos really <em>that</em> good? Both Firewall and iliana ranked them first overall in the preseason and discuss why they were so high on the Taco Baco. </p>



<p>Then, focus shifts to the Mild Subleague, where the Crabs and Moist Talkers are battling for control of the Mild Low. Can the Talkers keep rolling off of their Earlseason blessing? Or will all become Crab once again? What makes the Crabs so good, and what flaws might Canada have heading into the postseason?</p>



<p>The panel also discusses the Mild High, and considers the playoff hopes of the Steaks and Millennials, then asks if anyone can catch the Firefighters in the Wild High thanks to their Lateseason buff. </p>



<p>Finally, they discuss the expansion teams and the Tokyo Lift, and consider where each team needs to improve to make a splash in ILB in seasons to come.</p>



<p>You can watch the video below, or check it out live each week on Wednesday at 8 PM EST, 5 PM PST, or whatever else it might be in your time zone, live on <a href="https://glimesh.tv/dan">Dan&#8217;s Glimesh channel</a>. </p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<div class="jetpack-video-wrapper"><iframe loading="lazy" title="Midseason Power Ranking Review - Episode 1: Taco Baco" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/__CT8bYh8eg?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe></div>
</div></figure>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2021/03/10/bnns-midseason-power-ranking-review-taco-baco/">BNN&#8217;s Midseason Power Ranking Review: Taco Baco</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Blaseball News Network</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2021/03/10/bnns-midseason-power-ranking-review-taco-baco/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1226</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Blaseball Power Rankings for Season 13</title>
		<link>/2021/03/07/blaseball-power-rankings-for-season-13/</link>
					<comments>/2021/03/07/blaseball-power-rankings-for-season-13/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Firewall Andrews]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 02:48:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Power Rankings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1191</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The Hades Tigers were crowned champions and evolved ahead of one of the wildest postseason...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2021/03/07/blaseball-power-rankings-for-season-13/">Blaseball Power Rankings for Season 13</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Blaseball News Network</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The Hades Tigers were crowned champions and evolved ahead of one of the wildest postseason and election cycles we have seen in the recorded history of Internet League Blaseball. With every team seemingly making multiple moves over the Gods&#8217; Day break,  our experts were hard at work parsing the information needed to bring you power rankings and the hottest of takes.</p>



<p>So with no further delay, let&#8217;s get to the rankings. Teams are ranked based on average votes from our panel (listed at the bottom of the article), and each team&#8217;s movement since our Season 12 power rankings is noted alongside the team name.</p>



<h3 class="has-text-align-center" id="block-d9e5b211-b8a5-42c8-ad8e-eac49a5aedb1"><strong>24. <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f40c.png" alt="ðŸŒ" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> Ohio Worms</strong> <strong>[NaN]</strong></h3>



<p>The Worms feel right at loam at the bottom of the power rankings, as they secretly want to finish last to get their Bottom Dweller buff. But there are still things to like about the four-time champions who re-join ILB after some time away: Augusta Chadwell and Pitching Machine make for a nice one-two combo of hitters in the middle of the order, while veteran Farrell Seagull will bring a great approach at the plate to a lineup that seems rusty after some time away from the field. The biggest issue? The pitching. This is one of the weaker pitching staffs we&#8217;ve seen in recent ILB history and that&#8217;s why this team will struggle to avoid a PARTYTIME speedrun. </p>



<h3 class="has-text-align-center" id="block-d9e5b211-b8a5-42c8-ad8e-eac49a5aedb1"><strong>23. <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f531.png" alt="ðŸ”±" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> Atlantis Georgias</strong> <strong>[NaN]</strong></h3>



<p>The Georgias did not make any noise in their first election, choosing to use their Wills to improve their own team rather than go diving for players on other rosters. The result is a very unfamiliar group of players to ILB fans, but we are eager to see Mint Shupe and Rigby Friedrich take to the field, as both have very solid scouting reports. Expect plenty of scouts at The Bubble to start the season getting a look at this team and figuring out one of the more mysterious newcomers to ILB.</p>



<h3 class="has-text-align-center" id="block-d9e5b211-b8a5-42c8-ad8e-eac49a5aedb1"><strong>22. <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f3cb-fe0f-200d-2640-fe0f.png" alt="ðŸ‹ï¸â€â™€ï¸" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> Tokyo Lift</strong> <strong>[-2]</strong></h3>



<p>The election did not offer any game-changing buffs for the Lift, who enter the season as the first returning team to be ranked below 20 in our preseason power rankings. There is a core of a solid team forming, as Lance Serotonin is a very good power hitter and Coolname Galvanic is a rising star on the mound. There are just still a few too many weak points in this lineup that need to be pumped up with some PARTYTIME, Wills and Blessings. The Lift are getting closer, but unfortunately, they&#8217;re not looking like contenders in Season 13.</p>



<h3 class="has-text-align-center" id="block-d9e5b211-b8a5-42c8-ad8e-eac49a5aedb1"><strong>21. <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f6e0.png" alt="ðŸ› " class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> Core Mechanics</strong> <strong>[NaN]</strong></h3>



<p>Of the three teams re-joining ILB after prolonged absences, the Mechanics have easily the best pitching staff, with veteran PolkaDot Patterson joining the team alongside Shadows recruit Zoey Kirchner and experienced Core player Torus McGhee. Like the Georgias and Worms, there are definitely some players on this squad who show the rust of a team not tuned up and ready for ILB action, but the Mechanics offer the most upside with their stronger pitching staff and the potential for the Fourth Out for their batters.</p>



<h3 class="has-text-align-center" id="block-bb05182c-481c-421f-9c32-20f945ef2ee8"><strong>20. <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f48b.png" alt="ðŸ’‹" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> San Francisco Lovers</strong> <strong>[-11]</strong></h3>



<p>The Lovers underperformed in Season 12, lost Jaylen Hotdogfingers to a feedback swap, and lost Knight Triumphant to the Spies in a fairly one-sided trade. We still love Yosh Carpenter and Sandford Garner in the pitching rotation, but this team just isn&#8217;t adding any talent these days and will struggle to keep up in the hyper-competitive Mild Subleague. </p>



<h3 class="has-text-align-center" id="block-bb7483dd-490b-4630-a0cb-8f6fb6c3e6d4"><strong>19. <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f969.png" alt="ðŸ¥©" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> Dallas Steaks</strong> <strong>[-9]</strong></h3>



<p>Same can be said for Dallas, which simply did not make any moves that would help them keep up in a crowded and talented Mild Subleague. The Steaks will be pleased they kept their lineup in tact and didn&#8217;t lose superstars like Conner Haley, Rai Spliff, August Sky and Patel Beyonce, but there&#8217;s just not enough here to point to a surge up the standings in a Subleague now featuring the Crabs on top of the handful of teams that were battling until the final day for spots in the playoffs a season ago. </p>



<h3 class="has-text-align-center" id="block-0165719b-3bab-40ba-bedf-e97d0e005bba"><strong>18. <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f36c.png" alt="ðŸ¬" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> Kansas City Breath Mints</strong> <strong>[-4]</strong></h3>



<p>The good news: Hewitt Best moves to the leadoff spot and the Mints have a speedy star atop the lineup for the first time since Boyfriend Monreal was taken from them. The bad news: Jessica Telephone is no longer a Mint, meaning Marco Stink with a .845 OPS is now the best returning hitter from the Kansas City lineup. Sure, Joshua Watson swapping over for Telephone softens the blow a bit, but it has to leave a bad taste in the mouth of fans in Kansas City to see a superstar leave their team and not get a beneficial deal of their own this offseason.</p>



<p>Here&#8217;s what Paranundrox from SIBR had to say about the Mints: &#8220;While the team may have finally gotten rid of Pudge, they did so at the cost of two Wills and lost JT in the election, as well. On top of that, the return of the Crabs and the boosts to an already tight division means seeing them drop down substantially would not be surprising.&#8221;</p>



<h3 class="has-text-align-center" id="block-cfa949d9-6e48-4e2a-884c-cb42c5ef3668"><strong>17. <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f339.png" alt="ðŸŒ¹" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> Boston Flowers</strong> <strong>[-2]</strong></h3>



<p>We are probably too low on the Flowers. Sure, they don&#8217;t get to plug Nagomi Mcdaniel into their lineup, but the superstar batter is waiting in the shadows &#8230; just in case. But the team did pick up an energized Cory Twelve, who scouts say has totally overhauled their game this offseason, and the batting order is full of solid hitters from Jacob Haynes to SCORES BASERUNNER to Margarito Nava. However, the pitching staff is a bit thin since Twelve replaces King Weatherman rather than supporting him in what would be an improved rotation, so there&#8217;s still some growing to do for the Flowers.</p>



<h3 class="has-text-align-center" id="block-9f127eab-a927-4e39-82de-5ff0fa920378"><strong>16. <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f6a4.png" alt="ðŸš¤" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> Miami Dale</strong> <strong>[always]</strong></h3>



<p>We literally cannot help ourselves. We added more experts to the panel. We double-checked every ballot. The Dale always finish 16th in our rankings. However, I (Firewall Andrews) think the crowd is a bit too low on the Life of the Party. Beck Whitney and Francisca Sasquatch lead a solid batting order, with Logan Horseman impressing in offseason workouts following an Infusion. The pitching is solid, with Qais Dogwalker among the best in ILB and Sixpack Santiago a capable contributor. There&#8217;s still work to do, but this team is on the rise and could make some noise in Season 13.</p>



<h3 class="has-text-align-center" id="block-6ca920ce-603d-435b-963c-47052733a2b0"><strong>15. <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/2728.png" alt="âœ¨" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> Yellowstone Magic [+2]</strong></h3>



<p>The Magic climb two spots for the second straight season, slowly but steadily moving up the rankings as they add great players to their lineup. Chorby Short got a hitting upgrade while longtime rival King Weatherman joins the pitching rotation alongside Yellowstone veterans Inky Rutledge and Curry Aliciakeyes. The pitching is all there for the Magic, who just need a bit more from their offense to take the next step and battle for a playoff spot in a very tough Mild Subleague.</p>



<h3 class="has-text-align-center" id="block-2105f505-b383-400c-a819-b10414d2f162"><strong>14. <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f525.png" alt="ðŸ”¥" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> Chicago Firefighters [-3]</strong></h3>



<p>Are we just bored of the Firefighters? Why did they go down in our rankings after finishing with a strong record in Season 12 and getting some positive blessings in the offseason election? The team saw a boost to its pitching during workouts ahead of Season 13 and that should serve them well in the Wild League that&#8217;s loaded with offensive powerhouses. There&#8217;s nothing fancy about this club, but shoring up the pitching just a bit and sending struggling hitter Declan Suzanne to the Shadows for some extra batting practice should keep this team in the mix for the playoffs in the Wild Subleague.</p>



<h3 class="has-text-align-center" id="block-651c5b43-f23d-4623-b37f-87db8983cad8"><strong>13. <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f45f.png" alt="ðŸ‘Ÿ" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> Charleston Shoe Thieves</strong> <strong>[-8]</strong></h3>



<p>In an era of dominant pitching, the Flinch we see from Charleston hitters at the plate is just too much of a downside for an otherwise talented team. Some late-season partying and a surprisingly high-effort offseason of workouts has Tillman Henderson looking better than ever on the mound, while Pudge Nakatomo joins to give the team a batter that won&#8217;t watch the first strike go by every. single. time. There&#8217;s upside here, but in a stacked Mild Subleague, we can&#8217;t trust the Thieves to go much higher than the middle of the pack.</p>



<h3 class="has-text-align-center" id="block-c3f528ce-0959-4957-aec7-5ab924269b76"><strong>12. <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f357.png" alt="ðŸ—" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> Mexico City Wild Wings</strong> <strong>[+7]</strong></h3>



<p>The Wings made a major splash in the offseason, adding Jessica Telephone to their roster and moving Cell Barajas to the pitching rotation. These moves improve the Wings quite a bit, and they were already very solid with the incredible Burke Gonzales leading the way on the mound. The batting order has a few too many holes to call this team a true contender, but don&#8217;t be surprised if the Wings are making noise in the playoffs as a top four team and not a Wild Card in Season 13.</p>



<p>SIBR&#8217;s Paranundrox had this to say about the Wings: &#8220;They started out strong last season, and while they ultimately struggled (in part due to a number of late season games against the Tigers), swapping Cell Barajas into their rotation buffs an already absurd cast, and JT in the lineup gives them a jolt of power that can help end those 14 inning games at 1-0 a little sooner.&#8221;</p>



<h3 class="has-text-align-center" id="block-6e4be38a-7eb2-44f3-b253-42e34d7bc13f"><strong>11. <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f450.png" alt="ðŸ‘" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> Breckenridge Jazz Hands</strong> <strong>[+2]</strong></h3>



<p>Armed with Fourth Strike and a solid pitching staff, the Jazz Hands are another strong contender to claim one of the playoff spots in the Wild Subleague this season. Tamara Crankit has improved and should help set the table as the leadoff hitter in Season 13, while Wyatt Pothos is arguably the best pitcher in the entire league. But the rest of the pitching staff is good, but not great, and the batting order isn&#8217;t all on the same page just yet. This team is heading in the right direction.</p>



<h3 class="has-text-align-center" id="block-67cf3a4a-dbd9-4b14-9c28-085a4f957125"><strong>10. <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f575.png" alt="ðŸ•µ" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> Houston Spies</strong> <strong>[-4]</strong></h3>



<p>Adding Knight Triumphant to the batting order while getting some improvements out of Sosa Hayes during offseason workouts should help the Spies sneak up on the Wild Subleague this season after a middle-of-the-pack finish in Season 12. The pitching staff didn&#8217;t quite live up to pre-Grand-Siesta expectations, and if they can rebound, the Spies will be [redacted].</p>



<h3 class="has-text-align-center" id="block-ab2cfd02-2332-48bf-b12c-26f0a3fdecc8"><strong>9. <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f967.png" alt="ðŸ¥§" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> Philly Pies</strong> <strong>[+9]</strong></h3>



<p>Did we manage to underrate the Pies again? Probably. The underdogs from the City of Brotherly Love have some of the best batters in the league in Jode Preston and Jaxon Buckley, while boasting a solid pitching staff led by all-time great Elvis Figueroa. Both Ruslan Greatness and Huber Frumple have seemed improved during offseason camp at Tastycake Stadium, but there might not be enough improvement to fight to the top of one of the more competitive Subleagues in ILB history.</p>



<h3 class="has-text-align-center" id="block-5d4bd0b7-8d67-4900-8c11-168090e41a15"><strong>8. <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f980.png" alt="ðŸ¦€" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> Baltimore Crabs [NaN]</strong></h3>



<p>Get those claws back up, it&#8217;s Time for crab. The Crabs you know and love from seasons past aren&#8217;t entirely here, as many of the best players were sent around the league as Baltimore headed Up. But Forrest Best still leads a batting order that can run and defend very well &#8230; but might not hit that great. The pitching rotation is fantastic, led by veterans Brock Forbes and Adalberto Tosser and supported by newcomer Jacoby Podcast. Add in a fourth strike buff and it&#8217;s hard to not see this team challenging for the Mild Subleague playoffs in their first season back in the ILB.</p>



<h3 class="has-text-align-center" id="block-4d3bd762-85fa-40e1-b244-0d4efcdcf02c"><strong>7. <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f3dd.png" alt="ðŸ" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> Hawai&#8217;i Fridays</strong> <strong>[+1]</strong></h3>



<p>The Fridays were solid in Season 12, leaning on a solid rotation of pitchers and the superstar bat of Nagomi Mcdaniel to finish near the top of the Mild Subleague. But Mcdaniel is gone and one of their aces, Jaylen Hotdogfingers, is Flickering and could leave the roster at any time, and the Fridays can&#8217;t control who they get back in that exchange. But for me, the loss of Mcdaniel is the biggest reason the Fridays aren&#8217;t higher. The run production just isn&#8217;t promising enough to trust this team with a top five ranking.</p>



<h3 class="has-text-align-center" id="block-71305c6d-23a7-469f-8716-85072d0f074b"><strong>6. <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f3b8.png" alt="ðŸŽ¸" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> Seattle Garages</strong> <strong>[-2]</strong></h3>



<p>A game away from a title in Season 12, the Garages lose their star Pitching Machine and wound up gaining a less-than-ready Alaynabella Hollywood through a series of complicated transactions that also saw Goodwin Morin move to the batting order. Morin seems like a dominant batter, to be sure, but the seven-player pitching rotation has too many weak spots for us to trust Seattle with a spot in the top five. There&#8217;s tons of upside here and fun players to watch, but they will need to tune things up a bit more to make a run at a title again in the near future.</p>



<h3 class="has-text-align-center" id="block-8b0cb2dd-7155-49d5-9bc9-b1e0f07a6851"><strong>5. <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f4f1.png" alt="ðŸ“±" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> New York Millennials</strong> <strong>[+7]</strong></h3>



<p>There&#8217;s just something about this team that draws in splorts analysts every season. To be fair, the Mills did perform quite well in Season 12 before falling in an upset to the Shoe Thieves in the postseason. Hatfield Suzuki joins the batting order while Uncle Plasma bolsters a much-improved pitching rotation, and Sandie Turner is looking as strong as ever following in the footsteps of ILB legend Thomas Dracaena. Can they get it done in important games down the stretch? We shall see. But on paper, this team is looking incredible heading into Season 13.</p>



<h3 class="has-text-align-center" id="block-9b8932d1-a57d-4589-8c1c-22dfa6b1b246"><strong>4. <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f32e.png" alt="ðŸŒ®" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> LA Unlimited Tacos</strong> <strong>[+1]</strong></h3>



<p>Peanut Bong has retreated to the Shadows and Sexton Wheerer has been given an Infusion, virtually doubling the pitching talent of the Tacos in a single Gods&#8217; Day. Yummy Elliott looks like a solid No. 2 pitcher behind Wheerer, while the batting order for the Tacos is as amazing as ever, and looking a bit faster after putting in lots of Wind Sprints during workouts this offseason. </p>



<p>While I, Firewall Andrews, ranked the Tacos first, as I think they have a nearly unstoppable offense and two fantastic pitchers, others aren&#8217;t quite as high on the club from the Los Angelii. Paranundrox from SIBR had this to say: &#8220;I feel like they&#8217;re in a more fragile state than it seems. With a two pitcher rotation, they&#8217;re one bad day away from ruin, and their Season 12 offense suffered drastically compared to their Walk in the Park Showing &#8211; a team batting average of 0.246 (OBP 0.285) is not the most promising,  especially facing increasingly more boosted pitching staffs&#8221;</p>



<h3 class="has-text-align-center" id="block-42798168-73f9-444c-bdbf-30d7de03217d"><strong>3. <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/26aa.png" alt="âšª" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> Canada Moist Talkers [-2]</strong></h3>



<p>Surely losing a player like PolkaDot Patterson would doom any team, right? Not when you get massive gains from your batting lineup over the offseason and replace Patterson with a solid Doc Anice who, while not as amazing as the Squiddish Superstar, should hold together a solid pitching rotation that backs one of the best hitting lineups in the history of the splort. Fish Summer and York Silk are among the most talented players to ever step foot on a field, while Alston Cerveza and Eugenia Garbage are quite underrated and will make even more noise with their boosted stats. With Patterson still on board, this is probably our No. 1 team in our rankings. But without the Dot, we&#8217;ll settle for placing the Orb at No. 3.</p>



<h3 class="has-text-align-center" id="block-1f6a1f8d-263c-40a2-82f1-13227c40a4b4"><strong>2. <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f31e.png" alt="ðŸŒž" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> Hellmouth Sunbeams [+1]</strong></h3>



<p>Adding the best player in the league is a good way to keep yourself near the top of the BNN power rankings, and the Sunbeams did just that by picking up Aldon Cashmoney from their frenemies in Hades. Cashmoney joins Dudley Mueller in the most stacked lineup in Blaseball, while Sandoval Crossing leads a pitching staff that always does well enough to earn plenty of wins from this former championship squad. We would really like to see a bit more improvement to the pitching to keep them as contenders in seasons to come, but it&#8217;s hard to argue with that offense.</p>



<h3 class="has-text-align-center" id="block-640332f6-c94c-40df-ae53-7453cec1ccf3"><strong>1. <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f405.png" alt="ðŸ…" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> Hades Tigers</strong> <strong>[-]</strong></h3>



<p>Our experts almost reluctantly ranked the Tigers first, seemingly lacking a consensus for another team to put in this spot. Some believed the Moist Talkers were ready to make the leap, while others thought the Sunbeams would earn their second title. Still others picked the Tacos as the first overall team, myself included, and the Crabs even got a first-place vote. But no one is counting out the Tigers, with the entire panel ranking them at or near the top, and the incredible pitching staff is a big reason why. Matteo Triumphant helps fill the shoes of the departed Aldon Cashmoney, but the pitching staff led by Hiroto Wilcox is the real star of the show here. This team is fireproof and ready to head into Season 13 to earn a fourth title and take another step in their evolution as a dynasty in Internet League Blaseball.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<p>Thanks to our panel of experts from BNN and SIBR: <a href="https://twitter.com/FirewallAndrews" data-type="URL" data-id="https://twitter.com/FirewallAndrews">Firewall Andrews</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/BlaseballNews" data-type="URL" data-id="https://twitter.com/BlaseballNews">Benson &#8220;Nutty&#8221; Newton</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/haskins_luckey" data-type="URL" data-id="https://twitter.com/haskins_luckey">Luckey Haskins</a>, Frijoles Jones of <a href="https://twitter.com/unlimited_taco" data-type="URL" data-id="https://twitter.com/unlimited_taco">Taco News Unlimited</a>, Cowboy Moth, Joseph Ferrante (<a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCKftLCzXEiIH3U_0OxYd3hA">No Ichor on Youtube</a>, #Dargo4 on Discord), Ifh-Biff, the Data Efreet (<a href="https://twitter.com/BiffIfh">@BiffIfh</a> on Twitter), TK from <a href="https://twitter.com/BlaseballPolls">BlaseballPolls</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/Paranundrox">Paranundrox</a> of SIBR, Draywo from the BNN Discord, <a href="https://twitter.com/ilianaquorum">iliana </a>of SIBR, Joey T. Badger and <a href="https://twitter.com/Leto">Dan</a> of <a href="https://twitter.com/TheSplortsHub">The Splorts Hub</a>, Nago from the BNN Discord and <a href="https://twitter.com/ShadowsCorrespo">Shadows Correspondent</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2021/03/07/blaseball-power-rankings-for-season-13/">Blaseball Power Rankings for Season 13</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Blaseball News Network</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2021/03/07/blaseball-power-rankings-for-season-13/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1191</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Aldon Cashmoney is the new Blaseball GOAT</title>
		<link>/2021/03/06/aldon-cashmoney-is-the-new-blaseball-goat/</link>
					<comments>/2021/03/06/aldon-cashmoney-is-the-new-blaseball-goat/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Firewall Andrews]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Mar 2021 23:29:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Analysis]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1174</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Newly crowned as ILB Champion alongside the Tigers following a dominant season atop the Wild...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2021/03/06/aldon-cashmoney-is-the-new-blaseball-goat/">Aldon Cashmoney is the new Blaseball GOAT</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Blaseball News Network</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Newly crowned as ILB Champion alongside the Tigers following a dominant season atop the Wild League, Aldon Cashmoney has taken the step. They have made the leap.</p>



<p>They have passed <a href="/2020/09/28/why-workman-gloom-is-the-goat-greatest-of-all-time/" data-type="URL" data-id="/2020/09/28/why-workman-gloom-is-the-goat-greatest-of-all-time/">Workman Gloom</a> to become the greatest blaseball player of all time.</p>



<p>The Internet Series MVP and Firewall&#8217;s pick for Season 12 MVP stood tall during the &#8220;season of the pitcher&#8221; and put forth on of their best seasons as a pro, finishing the regular season with 41 home runs and 61 steals, the first 40/60 season in league history. </p>



<p>And that&#8217;s what sets Cashmoney apart from Gloom and any other player in Blaseball history. They can literally do EVERYTHING.</p>



<p>Ren Morin, Tigers teammate, told Blaseball News Network that Cashmoney&#8217;s casual jogging speed is enough to beat any other Hades player in a race. They get up to full speed so quickly that stealing bases is truly no issue.</p>



<p>And former Jazz Hands teammates knew Aldon would be a fantastic batter from early in their career.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Fridays player Aldon Cashmoney arrived this evening to Hlomecoming in vis typical effortless style- when asked for comment about vis ensemble, ve responded â€œARE YOU TALKING ABOUT ME. I HAVE. THREE MORE OF THESE AT HOMEâ€. <a href="https://t.co/pLLmhtYrTu">pic.twitter.com/pLLmhtYrTu</a></p>&mdash; bells<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f33f.png" alt="ðŸŒ¿" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> (@skelebells) <a href="https://twitter.com/skelebells/status/1310280284806418432?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 27, 2020</a></blockquote><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
</div></figure>



<p>Season 4 teammate and Jazz Hands stalwart Tamara Crankit remembered watching Cashmoney in batting practice and said &#8220;The ball just looked and sounded different coming off of their bat. It was special, it was unique &#8230; and it wasn&#8217;t really anything Aldon could teach us to do. It was just natural talent.&#8221;</p>



<p>At the end of Season 12, Cashmoney ranked first in all-time runs scored in Blaseball history &#8230; by a margin of 115 runs. That&#8217;s more than the margin from second to tenth. This is because they&#8217;re both second in home runs (driving themself in) and second in stolen bases (getting into scoring position) in league history. </p>



<p>There have been lots of great players in Blaseball history. But none has been better than Aldon Cashmoney.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">gg cashmoney</p>&mdash; stephen (@_stephenbell_) <a href="https://twitter.com/_stephenbell_/status/1368340158643277825?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">March 6, 2021</a></blockquote><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
</div></figure>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2021/03/06/aldon-cashmoney-is-the-new-blaseball-goat/">Aldon Cashmoney is the new Blaseball GOAT</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Blaseball News Network</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2021/03/06/aldon-cashmoney-is-the-new-blaseball-goat/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1174</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
